Hey, hey, hey.
Heat.
Good evening and good day everybody and
welcome back to the Askab show. This is
episode 335 and in today's episode we're
going to dis discuss mainly the ongoing
and escalating
war which is the war uh in in the Middle
East the Iran war the um American and
Israeli war attack on Iran and the
escalating circumstances. So we're going
to discuss that. Uh before we do that
obviously let me see who all is there on
the live chat. I can see a whole lot of
people. Good to see you all. I won't be
able to greet you all individually. Uh
Sam the gamer Manhattan, Sam the gamer,
real Vladimir Putin, Soldier Boy, uh
Shri Raach, Chandraaya, Namaha, Ritik
Pawar, Big Dog, Daksh G, Sam Winston,
Ankit Das, Prattard Dana,
GGS,
H Singh, Noah Wilson, Geopolitical Dubai
from Indor. Good evening. Uh who else do
we have? Chatanya Manuja. Um
who else? Who else? Lots of people. Uh
Shiva Sai H Singh, Reika Hlay. Good
evening. Jaram, Agam Senpai, Sergeant
Skylan, Amisha Mishwa,
Adwit Ashwini, Putin, Putin, KM, etc.
Uh who else? Rah Rahul is here. Rahul
with an interesting surname. Um Black
Panther is here. Soldier Boy once again.
Adwit Ashwini.
Let me see the latest ones. Must nil DH
He Samrat Chukl Chira Punjabi GXY
Prrenav 581 Pratim Anime Parati Pringa
Javalia. Good evening Aayush Singh
Pranam Sergi Prag Chawan Jam
Ak Shastavast.
Hello Himmanu Rajohit Prasan NH Vashish
Jri Vishnu okay mlevin good evening
commando is here from Iran Samar
Pusulkar situ rishiesh pi is here from
Bangalore sing arnav rishiesh matri
hello akshi shukla what's up terminator
66 bin salman from Saudi Arabia plank
cog talk to AI shik sahu karan singh
pund omnai
Suraj uh Honey Badger of Kolinga. Hello.
Ammon Tari Mahita Bushetti. Good evening
ma'am. Praguan good evening sir with
Rakshit. Hello Kabira Madhav.
Uh Nishai Agarwal Vlogs. Swami is here
from Swami is here also uh Vijay Vagela
Kamcho the tan 5G wise idiot and and so
many other people. I won't be able to
greet you all individually, but thank
you so much for being on this live
stream and there's a lot to discuss, a
lot to discuss. So, what's happened so
far? I mean, I did the last live stream
less than 48 hours ago, and so much has
happened ever since, right? In the
intervening 2-day period. This is the
third day of the uh war that we have in
the in the Middle East. And a lot has
happened. uh the war has expanded, it
has escalated and India has picked a
side very clearly. India has picked a
side. Now, why do I say that India has
picked a side? Well, let's take a look
at uh uh the Twitter account of our
Prime Minister, Mr. Modi, right? Let's
see what Mr. Modi has had to say about
the ongoing conflict. Um
what's the best way to put this? Is this
better? Is this better? I think this is
okay. Let's let's do it this way. So,
what has Prime Minister Modi said thus
far about this war? There's a whole lot
of activity on his Twitter account of of
course. Um, a lot of political uh tweets
of course that that is going to be
there. Uh, but yeah, let's go up and see
his tweets about the ongoing conflict.
So, this is 20 hours ago. Spoke with the
president of the UAE, my brother Shikh
Muhammad bin Z al- Nahan. strongly
condemned the attacks on the UAE and
condoled the loss of lives in these
attacks. India stands in solidarity with
the UAE in these difficult times.
Thanking thanked him for taking care of
the Indian community living in the UAE.
We support the escalation regional
peace, security and stability. So the
UAE is a very strong partner of India's
of of course we know that lots of
Indians live there about 40% of UAE's
population is of Indian origin and so
on. So and India has excellent relations
with the UAE. So this obviously makes
sense that this this tweet of course,
right? Okay. So so that's about the UAE.
Now we have a tweet in um Arabic. Uh
this is about the the same tweet in in
Arabic about the UAE. Then then Mr. Modi
had a telephone call
with Israel's Prime Minister Mr.
Netanyahu to discuss the current
regional situation conveyed India's
concerns about over recent developments
and emphasized the safety of citizens
civilians as a priority. India
reiterates the need for an early
sessation of hostilities. Okay. So
that's about Mr. Netanyahu with the same
tweet in Hebrew. Uh what else do we have
afterwards?
Uh now we have a tweet about uh
Bahrain had a productive telephone
conversation with the king of Bahrain.
His majesty king Hammad bin Isa al-
Khalifa. India condemns the attack on
Bahrain, obviously the attacks by Iran
on Bahrain and stands in solidarity with
Bahrain's people in this difficult hour.
I thank him for the steadfast support
extended to the Indian community in
Bahrain. U so India condemns the attacks
by Iran on Bahrain. Then it's about
Saudi Arabia. Discuss the evolving
situation in West Asia with Crown Prince
and Prime Minister of Saudi Arabia. His
Royal High Prince Muhammad bin Salman.
India condemns the recent attacks in
Saudi Arabia in violation of its
sovereignty and territorial integrity.
We agreed that the earliest restoration
of regional peace and stability is of
utmost importance. I thanked him for
looking after the well-being of the
Indian community in these difficult
times. So again, Prime Minister Modi
speaks with the the leader of Saudi
Arabia and condemns once again the
recent attacks by Iran on Saudi Arabia.
So India condemns the attacks on by Iran
on Saudi Arabia, by Iran on on Bahrain
and
um
the attacks by Iran on the UAE. Right?
So Iran is not mentioned by name but
it's obvious that Prime Minister Modi is
speaking about Iran and no other nation.
The attacks by Iran on these nations.
Okay. Uh now it's this this is the imp
interesting part. If you look at uh the
Twitter account of the prime minister of
Pakistan, Mr. Shahbaz Sharif, you will
see that he put out this tweet uh on the
1st of March, yesterday, early uh no e
early evening, the government and the
people of Pakistan joined the people of
Iran in their hour of grief and sorrow
and extend the most sincere condolences
on the martyrdom of his eminence ali.
Pakistan also concern expresses concern
about the violation of the norms of
international law because the attack on
a sovereign nation is a violation of
international law. The attack by Israel
and the US.
It is an age-old convention that the
heads of that heads of state and
government should not be targeted.
Absolutely. That's correct. We pray for
the departed soul and so on. Right. Um
Iranian people to bear this irreparable
loss. So, Prime Minister Sharif of
Pakistan offered condolences to the
people of Iran on the assassination
of Mr. of of the of the Supreme Leader
of Iran
say Ali Kabi. It is really interesting
that Prime Minister Modi made no such
statement of condolence of or or even
taking note of the assassination uh of
uh Mr. Kame.
So, what does this indicate? This
indicates that India has chosen what
side it is on. India has decided that we
are on the side of the US and Israel and
the and their allies in West Asia and uh
we are going to condemn the actions by
Iran which uh obviously as we know the
actions by Iran are in response to the
attacks on Iran. The actions by Iran are
in response to what happened on the
first day which is the assassination of
Mr. common a whether it's right or wrong
is a different matter but this is what
happened this is how the war started by
the Israeli and then US attacks on Iran
and the assassination of the head of
state essentially the head of state the
supreme leader of Iran right and India
has had a pretty good relationship with
Iran until the last few months until the
last few weeks actually right but now
India has decided that we're going to
stand with the US Israel and their
allies in West Asia and we are not
standing with Iran. We're not going to
condol the assassination of the supreme
leader and so on. So let's understand
one thing very clearly. India's decision
is a practical decision. It is not an
ideological decision. India has decided
to stand with the US, Israel, Israel and
the other nations for practical reasons
not for ideological reasons. It's not
about who is right, who's wrong. We all
know who's right, who's wrong. And that
is up to you to decide who's right and
who's wrong. But uh we know what
international law is. We know that
international law doesn't allow the
violation of a nation's sovereignty. Uh
assassination of the leader of a nation
and so on. But India has chosen to
disregard that. India has chosen to be
on the side of Israel, Iran, uh Israel,
US and the other nations that are allied
with them for practical reasons. Right.
So that's where we stand and a whole lot
has happened beyond that in the past 48
or so hours. So what's happened in the
last 24 hours? Let me just take a look.
Uh US and Israeli strikes on Iran
continued at high intensity. Okay.
Further attacks on missile
infrastructure and air bases. At least
one Iranian warship, probably multiple
Iranian warships. And Iran kept up its
missile strikes and drone strikes on
Israel and a number of other nations in
the Gulf region in the West Asia region.
in the Persian Gulf region, all the
nations that that host US military uh
personnel or US military infrastructure
on their territory, right? Um Hezbollah
has also gotten involved in the matter.
Hisbah has launched uh rocket attacks on
northern Israel. That's what one hears.
Okay. One hears that a number of
American fighter planes have been
brought down, have been shot down um in
Kuwait. Now, if you look at the uh map
of Kuwait, let's let's go to the map,
shall we? If you look at the map of
Kuwait, it's right. I mean, Kuwait is
this tiny little nation which borders
Iraq and Iran. Okay, West Kuwait. Kuwait
is here
and it essentially borders
uh three nations, Saudi Arabia, Iraq and
Iran. No direct connection with Iran, no
direct border, but it's you could say a
border nation with Iran. I mean, it's
it's right next door to Iran. So at
least three F15 fighter planes of the
United States have been brought down
have been shot down in Kuwaiti territory
or maybe along the Kuwait Iran boundary
border almost border right and one hears
that this was a friendly fire incident
maybe mistaken identity maybe Kuwait was
was shooting at uh drones or missiles
fired by Iran and maybe that's how they
ended up shooting down American fighter
planes but that remains to be seen some
US personnel have also been killed. U
warships have been sunk. At least nine
naval vessels have been sunk. Iranian
naval vessels from here there are there
were reports that an American aircraft
carrier has been targeted with ballistic
missiles by Iran. Right. So all that is
happening. Um and Iran has targeted at
least one Saudi oil installation that
belongs to Aramco, the big Saudi
company. And there's maybe the uh drones
or missiles were brought down but
there's been a big fire there and that's
why the operations have stopped over in
that uh refinery. Even Oman was hit by
Iran. Duke port in Iran was hit by
Iranian uh drones, Shahed drones
possibly uh and there's been some damage
there which is interesting because Oman
does not host any American military
installations or uh as far as I know
American military personnel right uh
that is what's going on and this war
continues it's it's obviously expanding
uh Dubai has been targeted uh lots and
lots of bombardment missile attacks on
on Isl Abu Dhabi was targeted. Uh Dubai
the the big hotel what the Bourj al Arab
was targeted and so much more. Right? So
this is an ongoing situation. Uh what we
are seeing is that Iran has pretty
sophisticated missiles, pretty
sophisticated ballistic missiles. Uh let
me try and find uh find the report. Give
me a second. Let me find I mean what
exactly Iran's ballistic missile
capabilities are like. They they have
made pretty interesting improvements in
their ballistic missiles. Let me give
you a second. Let me give Please give me
a second and I'll show you what's
happening.
Do I have it? Give me a second.
Obviously, I'm going to have to rely on
Twitter because uh Twitter has Yeah.
Okay. So, take take a look at this.
Okay. Take a look at this. Um,
so Iran its ballistic missiles once they
reenter the atmosphere and they they
come to an altitude of of about 10
kilometers or something in the terminal
phase what happens is that the Iranian
ballistic missiles are releasing a swarm
of about 25 penetration aids that whose
objective is to confuse the air
defenses. So when you have a Patriot
missile or iron dome missile going up to
intercept this ballistic missile, this
ballistic missile at at whatever
altitude suddenly releases a whole swarm
of about 25 penetration aids that that
behave just like that have the same
temperature and profile as the ballistic
missile itself. So they are hot glowing
uh objects that essentially mimic uh
from from an interceptor's perspective a
ballistic missile and that what it is
doing is that it's confusing the
interceptors the Patriot missiles and
the iron dome missiles and that's why
these these Iranian ballistic missiles
are able to successfully in many cases
hit their targets and after these
penetration aids are deployed the swarm
is deployed the uh ballistic missile as
warhead suddenly acquires hypersonic
velocity in the last 10 km or so. So,
its speed suddenly shoots up and then it
slams into the target. So, Iran has
pretty sophisticated capabilities and
it's causing a lot of trouble, you know,
it's causing a lot of trouble uh for
Israel and and the American uh missile
defense systems, the Iron Dome and so
on. So, there's been a apparently a lot
of damage in Israel and that situation
is ongoing. Iran has also decentralized
its military command. So Iran how many
let's see how many provinces does Iran
have? Let's let's quickly take a look at
how many provinces Iran has. Um how
many pro must be about 30
does Iran have? Must be 30 provinces.
31 provinces. So each province is now
going to have its own IRGC command.
Okay? And they will all act
independently the the revolutionary
guards command. So each province will
have its own army, its own command and
control infrastructure, its own
missiles, everything. And they're going
to act completely independent
independent of each other. So even if
the Iranian high command is completely
decimated, decapitated, taken out, Iran
keeps fighting. Even if Iran is defeated
at the center at Thran and let's say
American or Israeli forces are coming
in, Iran will now fight from 31
different angles, 31 different
independent armies. So even if Iran is
defeated, this can go this can this can
cause a multiple year year-long
insurgency that will fight the occult
occupiers or attempted occupation
uh attempts of Iran. So Iran has clearly
thought this out and they seem to have
very very large stockpiles of missiles
and drones. Okay, the Shahed drones,
loitering drones and all. And the thing
is this
um these systems like the Iron Dome
missile system, the Patriot missile
system which are air defense systems
which intercept missiles. Each missile
of these
each each interceptor missile costs more
than a million dollars. But these shahed
drones, they cost $20,000.
So the the economics doesn't make sense
to bring down a $20,000 drone. They're
going to have to spend, you know, you're
going to have to waste at least one
missile that's at least a that cost at
least a million dollars. So Iran may
have very very large quantities of these
drones and this could cause a rapid
depletion of the stocks
of Iron Dome and Patriot missiles. Then
what do you do once you run out of these
missiles? Then you are setting targets.
So yeah, I mean Iran has really really
thought this through. And I'm sure that
they still have many tricks up their
sleeves. Now what is going in favor of
the US? Every time the Iranians launch
missiles, the American uh surveillance
system, the satellites and whatever else
they can hopefully from their
perspective start detecting where the
launches are happening from. So if these
are silos in the ground, they can be
taken out. If these are transporter
erector launcher vehicles, it'll it's
harder to take these out. So the
Americans and Israelis will soon start
identifying where the launches are
happening from and try and take those
launchers out. So it's a game of cat and
mouse that we are seeing right now. And
right now Iran is doing a pretty good
job actually of defending itself and
actually um attacking uh the various
targets that they have in mind. So that
is the situation. It's it's uh nobody's
winning or losing the war. Iran is doing
a good job defending itself. Iran has
been attacked, right? Iran did not start
the attack. So, you could say that Iran
is defending itself. It's doing a pretty
good job thus far, but it's very early
days in the war. Um, if this goes on for
let's say a week, then the uh stocks of
defensive missiles like the Iron Dome
and so on may start running out. And
then what does the US do? What does
Israel do? Does the US ask for a
ceasefire? That will be humiliating for
the US. But will Iran last a week also?
That's also a question. So in 7 days
time, will Iran be still be fighting? If
it is still fighting, then it's
advantage Iran because the stocks of
defensive missiles will will definitely
get depleted or start getting depleted
depleted by the time. If that happens,
what does Trump do? Trump will not
tolerate any humiliation. Will he resort
to more powerful measures?
What kind of powerful measures are we
talking about? Well, there are all kinds
of powerful measures, including nuclear
weapons, but if Iran is decentralized
and it has 31 different armies fighting,
how many nukes can you could you
possibly use? Right? So, the situation,
it's not a cakewalk for the US and
Israel. It's pretty hard. Iran is
showing up a real fight. It's it's
giving a real fight, right?
So for us outside of this entire thing
as for us as neut neutral observers what
does this all mean? Well you know the
straight of hormones is closed for the
first time in history. What's the
straight of hormones? Let's let's go to
the map. The straight of hormones the
Iranians have closed it. Okay. No ship
can pass through without getting
targeted by Iran. This here this
geographic choke point is the straight
of hormones and much of the oil that's
that comes to India and China and Japan
passes through this choke point. This is
currently closed. So India is now not
getting oil any oil that was flowing
into India from the UAE or Saudi Arabia
or Kuwait or whatever Iraq or wherever.
And the same goes for China. India has
strategic oil reserves. China also has
strategic oil reserves. But this is a
huge issue for India. China and Japan.
So, India seems to have restarted its
Russian oil deliveries. Yeah. Okay. And
China also has access to Russian oil.
But u very soon there's going to be if
this continues there's going to be a oil
shock in the world. Oil prices will
shoot up massively and because of that
the prices of your tomatoes and onions
and everything will shoot up very very
massively if if this goes on the next 7
days for for 7 days, 10 days or
whatever. So that's an immediate impact
for India, for China, for Japan, for
Pakistan, whoever else. Uh, and also the
Iranians are alleging that the
Pakistanis allowed American aircraft to
use Pakistani airspace for attacks on
Iran. So Iran could potentially target
Pakistan now. Yeah. So this is
escalating.
This is escalating. Iran is is not being
defeated as of now. Iran is fighting and
there are serious questions as to how
long the US can keep keep this up and
also how long Iran can survive right
it's not like Iran is winning Iran is
holding its ground right now but how
long can it hold its ground and if it
holds its ground for a significant
amount of time then what can the US in
Israel do right so big questions up in
the air right now we don't have answers
we'll have to wait and watch day by day
how this goes so that is the situation
in brief. Now let's see let's take
questions shall we? Black Panther says
today evening US secretary of state war
the secretary of war press briefing this
war is not for Iran regime change
operation. What is the reason the US has
changed its position? Right. So when the
war started President Trump said that we
are this was all about regime change.
Prime Minister Natanyahu also said that
we we want to defeat Iran and change the
regime. Right?
That's they did not use those exact
words but that was the meaning that was
the meaning of their statements regime
change in Iran clearly unambiguously
regime change in Iran. Now it looks like
there is a different there's something
else coming from the US. So I haven't
seen this press briefing
but if if it is true that they're now
saying it's not for regime then what is
it all about? What is it all about?
Right? If you don't change the regime,
then why did you launch this war? You
want to defeat Iran militarily and then
continue the regime to to go on. Is that
what you want? But then why did you say
in the beginning it was regime change?
So why has the US changed its position?
Because maybe they have recalibrated
this their their expectations based on
how the war has gone thus far. Right?
Iran has not been ruled over. Iran is
fighting back very hard actually as of
now at least. So maybe that's a one of
the reasons why this statement may have
come out of the US. Next question. Akam
Senai says almost 50% of India's oil
passes via the straight of hormones. Why
are some Indian geo experts celebrating
USIsrael strikes which risks India's oil
supply next funded internal conflicts
among us? Look, I don't know why Indian
geopolitical experts say this or say
that or why they say what they do. I I
can't possibly comment about why they
say what they do. What they say I don't
know why do some Indians why are some
Indians I mean there are plenty of
Indians on social media who are
celebrating uh the US and Israel strikes
on Iran. See for us we are not involved
in this matter right so ideally Indians
should be neutral about this. Um but
yeah I don't I can't possibly give you
an answer about why are some Indians
celebrating this. This is obviously the
longer this war lasts, the more hardship
India will face because all oil oil
prices rise up. Oil prices will rise
significantly if this war continues. If
the straight of hormones remains closed
uh for a week, 10 days, 2 weeks, it's
going to be bad for India and many other
countries including China. So I don't
know Indians are emotional people and I
don't know if how Yeah. So I I can't say
I can't tell you why they are
celebrating. Yeah, Sergeant Skylon says,
"Is IMECH just a pipe dream? India,
Middle East, Europe trade corridor?"
That's IMC. So, what is this thing and
what is it like? So, the idea of IMC is
that let's say we have ports in Western
India like Mumbai for example. Okay.
From there, we can um you can we can we
can connect with the Arabian Peninsula
maybe via Oman, via UAE or wherever.
Then we can send goods into the Arabian
Peninsula. They will build railways and
other other infrastructure to have the
goods cross the Arabian Peninsula. Then
you can enter Israel via Jordan or
wherever. And from Israel in Israel we
have Hifa port which we are operating
which the Adani group is operating at
least some terminals are being operated
by the Adani group. So from Hifa we can
have more ships going in into perhaps
Cyprus or and Greece right the port of
roads and other other ports in Greece.
And from there we can connect to Europe.
So it can be a back and forth kind of
trade corridor and which will be
beneficial for India, for uh the Arabian
nations, for Israel and for the European
nations, right? Because this will enable
more trade at at cheaper uh costs. It'll
be cheaper. So that's the idea of IMC.
Is it a pipe dream? Well, when West Asia
is so unstable. So when was the concept
of IMC put put forth?
it it uh was spoken about first if I
recall correctly during the 2023 uh G20
summit in India in in Delhi right uh in
the last quarter of 2023
uh and immediately after that we had the
Hamas attack on Israel which completely
destabilized the region and IMAC could
not take off at the time the Saudis
wanted it to start immediately
um so yeah you had the Gaza situation
which went on for a long time then the
Houthi situation
um Babal Mandr was closed for a while
and so on. So uh that's why no uh
progress could be made on building the
infrastructure and now you have this war
in the region which obviously means you
can't build any infrastructure there at
the time. So as long as the Middle East
remains conflict prone and unstable IMAC
is going to rem remain a pipe dream. If
the West Asia region can be stabilized
so that there is no more no more war, no
more conflict, then IMAC can possibly
take off. Until then, it is a pipe
dream.
Putin
says, "Can Iran turn into America's
Ukraine if it sends troops?"
Well, the question is, if the US sends
troops into Iran, you know, boots on the
ground, can Iran turn into America's
Ukraine? It depends on multiple factors.
The Iranians have decentralized their
armed, you know, their military command
and now you have 31 different armies
fighting independently. That can
significantly
cause significant problems to any
invading forces, right? Significant
problems because it's not as easy as
taking out the command and control the
the leadership. You have 31 different
sets of leadership and they will all
have their fallback options each of
them. So, it's going to be very
difficult. Secondly, who how long can
Iran keep fighting? If it if nobody
supplies it with more arms and
ammunition. So that is also a factor. If
Russia decides to supply Iran with arms
and ammunition, then well then Iran can
possibly keep fighting for a long time.
So this is going to be very tricky, very
dicey for any invading forces. Iran's
going to fight. I mean we we you had
this horrible incident of of this of an
attack on an Iranian Iranian school in
which hundreds of school girls were
killed. Even if Iranians don't support
the regime of the Ayatollas, this sort
of thing is going to unify the Iranian
nation, the people of Iran, right? So
it's not going to be easy. The the
common citizens may may fight if
required. I think the objective of the
US is to balkcanize Iran actually
because in Iran only 50% of the
population is Persian. The rest are
various other ethnicities like
Azarbaijanis and Arabs and balois and
whatnot. So I think the objective is to
balkcanize Iran. Actually balkcanization
is a favorite strategy of the west.
Division, partition, balcanization, all
of that. So maybe that's an objective
but it's going to be tough.
Omisha says arresting eliminating
leaders is the new normal now.
Nationalists are saying it's better to
side with Israel. Iran is also
retaliating. Is Iran capable of a long
war? So first of all, yes, uh
international law apparently no longer
exists. Uh you can now assassinate world
leaders. You can you can arrest and
kidnap world leaders. That's what the US
is doing now. They kidnapped Mr. Maduru,
the president of Venezuela. And now they
have assassinated Mr. Kabi the elderly
uh supreme commander supreme leader of
Iran. So it's it's it's perfectly fine
if the US does it or if you are a US
ally who does it. Yeah. So see look what
is now happening in the world. It
actually is the world defaulting to to
normal. The world reverting to normal.
No more nicities. Power is going to be
shown and flaunted and used openly.
Whoever is powerful can do what they
want. Whoever is weak they they have to
tolerate whatever happens and that's how
the world has always been. The past 70
80 years was kind of an anomaly an
aberration and we are reverting to a
world where might is right. Might was
still right in the past 80 years but it
was done in a very subtle way. Now it's
just open. Uh yeah nationalists are
saying it's better to side with Israel.
Well I don't know.
I would say look from India's
perspective we should remain neutral
about this. um we should not take this
side or that side. But we have taken
sides. Now the prime minister of India
has clearly uh made a decision then
we're going to side with Israel and the
US and uh their allies in West Asia. So
yeah. So if nationalists are saying it's
better to side with Israel then the
prime minister clearly agrees with them.
Uh and Iran is retaliating is it capable
capable of a long war? Well time will
tell but it I think it is capable of a
long war.
Black Panther says Russia Ukraine war
under the Biden.
They refused to talk with Putin. Trump
came power deal is on. Putin delay
reason. US put more pressure on India.
Modi got played. I'm
Yeah. Russia Ukan war went on. Yeah.
Okay. Under Biden they refused. The US
refused to talk with Putin. Yeah. True.
Trump came. Power deal is on. Power
deal. Which power deal? Trump met with
Putin and uh he tried to Trump wanted an
immediate end to the war. That's
obviously not going not that obviously
did not happen. Putin delay reason India
put more pressure on India. Putin
delayed agreement that's why US is
putting more pressure on India. Putin's
job primary job is to take care of his
nation and his national interest. His
job is not to worry about what happens
to Modi or India. Right? Putin's first
and only responsibility is to look out
for Russia's national interest. You
can't blame Putin for delaying if the
Americans say that sign a lopsided
agreement. Why should Putin sign it?
Right? Why should Putin give America
what it wants on America's terms? Right?
So yeah, Modi got played. No, Modi has
not got played. India isn't powerful
enough to to to
remain neutral in in this matter. Modi
has not got played.
Adi Pradhan says views on Mexico
conflict US involvement. So it's an old
story in Mexico in in South America in
in in Central and South America. It's an
old story. These cartels and all that's
been going on forever forever forever.
The Americans have launched multiple
wars on on drugs but they remain the
primary consumer of all drugs produced
in the world. For example, I can show
you something you know something that
happened when I was a kid. Okay? When I
was a kid, this is what happened. See,
operation Condor,
okay,
it was u a campaign of political
repression by right-wing dictatorship of
the southern co of South America. Uh
politic in Pino etc. was about drugs,
wasn't it? If I remember correctly,
drugs. Well, it has no mention of drugs,
but this was about drugs. Anyhow, so the
Americans have been fighting wars on
drugs against cartels and all for a very
long time. Uh but the cartels still keep
supplying America with drugs and right
now we have this conflict that's
happened in Mexico. A cartel leader got
killed and the cartel went after the
government and so on. Is there US
involvement? I suppose whatever happens
in the Americas there is some level of
US involvement in that.
Prattana says uh I have seen the divine
justice a few years ago. a female
politician was sidelined by her own
party due to Arabs
also caused riots and killings. Um I'm
I'm not sure who you're referring to. In
which country you're talking about
India, you're talking about somebody
else? Some other country?
Um
due to Arabs? I have no idea what you're
talking about unfortunately. I'm not
getting the context. Is it is it a
female politician in India or some other
country? Not sure. Sorry Ankit Das.
Thank you very much sir. Thank you.
Ritik Paw says, "If India becomes an
American vasal, shouldn't we blame the
government? Even weak weaker governments
in the past did not bow down. Why should
we tolerate it this time for any reason?
If India becomes an American vasal, who
is to blame?" The government of India is
to blame clearly. See, in the past, we
had weaker governments. Sure, let's say
in the 20th century, we had much weaker
governments. India was a much weaker
nation at the time. But in the 20th
century, there was a balance in the
world. You had not one superpower. You
had two superpowers. So you could play
one against off against the other.
That's what you could do in the 20th
century. Today the world is lopsided.
There's only one superpower. There's
nobody who can stand up to America's
might.
And that's why if the Americans ask us
to make us make a choice, we have to
make a choice.
Now the in and in that scenario what
what how can we blame the government of
India? India India is simply not
powerful enough. But the truth is if we
had put our house in order in the past
10 12 15 years India may possibly have
been in a situation where we could stand
up for ourselves and not become
anybody's vasal.
If we had for example uh cleaned up the
uh military acquirement processes of of
weapons systems and all and if we had
focused fullfledged
or full force on indigenization of of
defense equipment and if we had acquired
somehow or the other 200 more fighter
planes instead of instead of 36
and if we had ensured that we have
indigenous AI systems that are being
built and if we if we had ensured that
we are not penetrated by foreign social
media and AI and technology and all that
if we had done all those things if we
had set up a a highquality R&D
environment which needs educational
reforms and all that if we had done all
those all those things in the past 15
years
then we would not possibly perhaps be in
a situation where we have to accept
American uh overlordship over India. So
from that perspective we should blame
the government. Yes. But if you forget
what's happened in the past 15 years and
look at India's position today, then
India is simply not strong enough and
that's why the government of India today
has no choice.
Wishnav, thank you very much sir.
Adi Pradhan says view on recent Indian
noam. I have no idea. I've not looked
into no times but let's take a look at
it. Okay. Uh
India uh India come on India no time. Do
we have any notam? No time summaries
Mumbai airport stops flight de d d d d d
d d d d d d d d d d d d d d d d d d d d
d d d d d d d d d d d d d d dions. Uh
I'm not sure what the not time is. Is it
about the India diverting flights etc
because of the situation in West Asia?
Well, that makes complete logical sense,
right? So I'm not sure if there's any
notam related to missile tests or
whatever. But if this is the note I'm
taking into consideration the situation
in West Asia, well that makes complete
logical sense.
All right. KRS N Krishna is singularity
has become a new member. Thank you so
much sir. Thank you so much. Welcome to
the channel's membership.
Batarana says India votes against the US
in and Israel in the UN. Why? Well, it
depends on the issue. India's support to
various issues or or various voting
situations is issue based.
So I am sure there are many uh cases in
which India votes on the side of the US
and Israel also right. Um so it depends
on the issue that we're voting about
that is being voted for or against. Um
it's not like India has a pattern of
always voting against the US and Israel
in the UN. That's not the case. There
are lots of UN votes in which India has
been has voted on the side of the US and
Israel. So it depends on the specific uh
issue that is being voted for. Yeah.
Mr. Rohit says why Russia doesn't did
not share nukes with Iran like the US
does. The US does not share nukes with
anybody whatsoever.
The US doesn't share nukes with anybody,
but it does place nukes on other nations
territory. Uh let's let's see. Okay.
Yeah, that's a good question. It's a
good question for conceptual
understanding. Um, in which nations
um has the the US
deployed
deployed nuclear weapons. It's going to
be mostly uh NATO nations. So let's see
five NATO nations. Belgium, Germany,
Italy, the Netherlands, and Turkey. So
the US deploys its own nuclear weapons
in a bunch of countries. Five they are
typically members of NATO. NATO nations
are not sovereign nations. They are
nations that are essentially whose
military and whose fate is controlled by
the US. So the US deploys American
nuclear weapons on those nations
territories
and those American nuclear weapons are
only controlled by American personnel
not by the personnel of those nations
Belgium, Germany, Italy, Netherlands,
Turkey. No Belgian personnel has access
have access to American nuclear weapons.
No Turkish personnel have access to
American nuclear weapons. They can't I
suppose they don't even get to see the
nuclear weapons. The it is American
military personnel and technical
personnel who have the custodianship of
those American nuclear weapons. America
doesn't share nuclear weapons with
anybody whatsoever.
Okay, that is something we have to
understand. Nuclear technology, nuclear
weapons are not to be shared. It's it's
too sensitive and it's too critical and
that's why Russia has not done that with
with Iran.
Krishna singularity says Jam thank you
very much Jam to you indeed. I've been a
student of yours since 2020. You have
inspired my way of thinking greatly.
Thank you for everything do you you do.
Thank you so much sir. Such a nice such
a nice thing to say. Thank you so much.
I'm glad that you have learned
something. Hopefully it's more than
something from me. I'm I'm very glad.
You are most welcome indeed sir. Thank
you.
Anu Jan says in the last two days we saw
in Iran's hypersonic missiles could not
be stopped by Israel in the USA. Why are
they not hitting the USS Abraham Lincoln
by these missiles?
You don't
you don't do everything on day one.
Right.
You don't do that on day one. You don't
show all your cards on day one.
Let me give you an example another
example of what Iran hasn't done thus
far. Okay. I am not suggesting this
should be done. I'm just saying this is
another thing Iran has not done this
far. Okay, let's go to the map. I am by
please don't misconstrue what I'm saying
over here that I am suggesting Iran
should do this. I am not suggesting
anything. I'm just saying I'm giving you
another example of what Iran has not
done. Let's go to Israel, the nation of
Israel. Okay. Now let's go to um
satellite image imagery. So we have
Israel. Now we have the city of the town
of Beer Shiva. Okay. Near the s the town
of Ber Shiva Shiva we have Dimona
and near Dimona
we have this
pretty clearly visible
installation is it? No this is not the
one. Uh where is it?
It's going to be very clearly visible.
Oh here we are the negative desert. The
negative nuclear research center.
Okay. Okay. And we have nuclear reactors
over here. And this is allegedly this is
allegedly where Israel's nuclear weapons
are produced and so on. We don't know
whether they are stockpiled whatever. My
point is see I'm not suggesting that I'm
not suggesting for one second that Iran
should target this. My point is this is
another you know potential target Iran
has. Right? So there are aircraft
carriers, there are nuclear
installations, there are many other
targets that Iran could possibly
potentially want to choose, but Iran
won't do it on day one.
Depends on how serious the situation is.
So depending on the seriousness and
severity of the challenge and that Iran
is facing, depending on that Iran will
take decisions. So if Iran is in very
bad situation in in let's say x number
of days then they may decide to hit such
targets
right and the Israelis would have kept
separate missiles to defend these sites
obviously. So this is the way war is
done right Iran will not hit everything
on day one.
Iran obviously will be hoping that the
Americans and Israelis will ask for a
ceasefire sometime soon. They'll be
hoping for it. See, if Iran hits an
aircraft carrier, then that's a
humiliation for the US. And then Trump
has no choice but to go allin.
Iran doesn't want a situation where
Trump has to go all in and all out
against them, which means destruction of
Iran. The US can destroy Iran actually.
Right. And if they hit a nuclear power
plant or or nuclear research station of
Israel, then Israel may use certain
weapons it would otherwise not use. So
that's the point. Escalation is done
step by step gradually. You don't go
from 0.1 to 100 straight away. That's
the point.
I am Anonymous says remember the
statement of Ajit Dwal's statement on
revenge. That was the biggest clue which
we all missed. What was the statement?
I I'm not aware of Ajit Dwal's statement
on revenge. Uh let me see if I can find
out. Okay. Uh Ajit Dwal's statement on
revenge. Ajit
Ajit Dwal's statement on revenge.
Oh, I can do that. That's fantastic. Um
January 2026, he urged youth to avenge
our history to build a stronger India. A
powerful force for nation building and
revenge for history.
Okay, I'm not sure what u is the clue
for what we all missed. Uh maybe I'm not
looking looking at the correct
statement. Maybe it was a statement made
five years ago. I don't know. Uh but I'm
not sure what the context is. If you can
give me the statement, then maybe I can
get more context. All right. Uh Han
Sharma as always wants to remind me
about the movie Tumbad. Right now I'm
not in a position to watch Tumb. I'm
looking at what's happening in West
Asia. But yes, too bad Shik Hami G
passed away without watching Tumbad.
Okay. Okay.
Okay. Banticor says, "Do not despair,
sir. Even if we are aligned, it doesn't
mean vaselization. Our country will
change. Our civilization will not fall
or be erased. It's evolving as it always
has. The deas isolation will reverse in
due time. An anonymous G, thank you very
much for this very positive message. I
agree with you. We should not despair.
You know, we should always be positive.
We should always be optimistic.
while being positive and optimistic, we
should work towards making India better
and stronger as a nation and also
civilizationally. So I I thank you for
this very positive statement and I
completely agree with you sir.
Uh Putin etc says do you miss the USSR?
Would the US have dared to do this if
they were still there? Unfortunately
Russia stuck with Putin and his Jewish
oligarchs with Israeli citizenship.
Okay, I'm not aware of Jewish oligarchs
and Israeli citizenship and all. Russia
has put in. Look, do I miss the USSR?
Not necessarily. Look, when I was a kid,
I was scared of the USSR because I was
completely influenced by whatever I read
in English and by I'd spend spent a few
years as a kid in the West and so and so
on. So, my entire world view was shaped
by the West
and I was as a as a kid I was scared of
the USSR.
Uh, today I see the USSR very
differently. Of course, right? Because
I'm no longer a 80-year-old. I see it
very differently. Do I miss it? No, it's
gone. What's the point of missing what's
gone? What's the point of be of wishful
thinking and all? I don't miss the USSR.
It's gone. It's just a fact of life. Uh,
would the US have dared to do this if
the USSR was still around? No. No way.
No way.
Yeah, it wouldn't have happened if the
USSR was still uh in existence.
Vidya Manar says, "Iran is fighting
openly. How is it non-s sovereign?"
Ma'am, that's a very very good question.
Iran is fighting openly. Iran is
fighting without the support of anybody
else without any substantial support
from either Russia or China. So the So
Vidi is asking how is then Iran non-s
sovereign. Right?
Here's my answer to you ma'am.
Here's my answer. Take a look. So this
is a tweet by me from about an hour and
a half ago,
right?
This is the the what you are if you are
a viewer of this channel, you would have
known this for years. The Chavda
sovereignty framework since 2021. There
are only six sovereign nations on earth.
The US, Russia, China, India, Israel,
and Iran. Every other nation exists as a
semi- sovereign state or a geopolitical
vasal. So Iran is fighting for survival
without Chinese or Russian support.
Therefore Iran is the newest addition to
the list. If you want this graphic, if
you want this image, simply go to my
Twitter profile, you will find it there.
So I have added, see this is an evolving
framework. It evolves depending on the
situation.
Okay? If Iran loses this war in let's
say a month's time then I will again
remove Iran from this. Until now I had
not put Iran there because Iran was
significantly dependent on Russia and
China for a variety of things. But right
now today at this very hour Iran is
fighting without anyone's support
right it's fighting for its survival.
It's fighting for its sovereignty. As of
today as of right now at least Iran is a
fully sovereign nation. So there are six
fully sovereign nations in the world.
And I will have to revisit each nation
and see once again in a while whether
they deserve to be fully sovereign out
of those six how many actually deserve
to be there. We will see maybe in a
week's time maybe in a month's time I
will revisit that. Maybe the number will
change. Maybe the number may go down to
four perhaps. Yeah. But it's a very very
timely question you are asking Vidi and
you are right.
Kashi says sucks India align with
imperialists but what to do? Well, when
you are weak, you have no choice. When
you are weak, you have to make pragmatic
practical choices. The best best choice
you can make given the circumstances and
given the options that you have. It
sucks. It sucks.
Ideally, we would like to be completely
neutral and not aligned with anybody.
But when you are in a position of
weakness, this is what happens to you.
The biggest sin in geopolitics is
weakness.
Aris manticor says and it's because of
people like you. This generation will
not sleep upon our history nor will my
children either. The government of India
will change slowly in a most infur
infuriating manner but it will not
surrender. One hope so and thank yeah
one hope so. One hopes so I'm pretty
sure the government of India will not
surrender. The change may happen very
slowly perhaps as it tends to do uh in
post 1947 India
slow motion change yeah but I don't
think the government of India will
surrender so I agree with you there and
thank you so much for for your very kind
words thank you so much
Junat says do you think if Iran had
played its cards better since the '9s or
at least by the early 2000s by avoiding
unnecessary regional antagonism
situation today might have been very
different.
See, Iran has simply um responded
to the evolving situation in its region.
Okay. After the end of the first cold
war, Iran slowly found itself being
surrounded,
being encircled by American military
bases and installations and presence
in its vicinity.
Another thing that happened was that
even during the first cold war in the
20th century, the United States used
Iraq as a stick to beat Iran with in a
very bloody way.
in a in a very damaging way. So Iran
and Iran has this had had this enemity
with the US since 1979. So Iran was very
clear and very pragmatic about who its
enemies were and the US obviously
surrounded and encircled Iran. So Iran
also
went ahead and played the geopolitical
game of power projection. It cultivated
uh allies or what what they call proxies
in its surrounding region. Which allies
did it have? Let's go to the map. Okay.
Uh which proxies did or allies did Iran
cultivate? Iran cultivated proxies such
as the Shia population of Iraq which is
about 40 50%. It cultivated proxies in
the Assad uh government, Assad regime in
Syria, the in Liberan, Hisbullah. Um the
uh Shia
population of Yemen, the Ansar faction
and all um and so on. So Iran said that
we will not sit down and be reactive, we
will be proactive. If you are encircling
us, we will also cultivate proxies and
and create our own power projection uh
capabilities in the region. So Iran
played the game much more robustly than
India typically ever does. Right? And
that actually possibly has helped Iran
out. Iran has not tried to antagonize
everybody. The antagonism goes,
it's caused by other factors. There are
religious issues, Shia, Sunni issues,
etc. The very fact that Iran is so large
and powerful that scares nations in
Saudi Arabia and other nations. So Iran
has not been antagonizing,
you know, it its neighbors. It's just
been positioned that way and its
neighbors have been used u by the US to
encircle Iran. The only thing that Iran
could have done better, okay, which
could possibly not have caused the
situation that it finds itself in that
one thing Iran could have done better is
to become an open openly declared
nuclear nuclear weapon state.
But for some reason, it did not do that.
And that's why Iran finds itself in the
situation. Look at North Korea. Does
anybody dare touch North Korea? North
Korea is not fully sovereign. It's
completely dependent dependent on
firstly China and secondly Russia for a
whole lot of things. But nobody's going
to dare to invade North Korea because
North Korea has nuclear weapons and the
means to deliver those nuclear weapons
far far away. That's why nobody messes
with North Korea. If Iran had done that,
it would not find itself in the
situation it finds itself in right now.
That's one thing it could have done
differently.
Hershel Singlasses Hershel Singlass
says, "Our ties with Iran were purely
transactional. Amen never condemned the
terror attacks on India. He opposed the
CAA. He called the Delhi riots a Muslim
massacre. He repeatedly urged support
for the so-called Kashmir Muslim
struggle." Yes. Yes. About Kami, I
agree. K's words,
verbal statements, you could consume a
lot of those statements as being
anti-India. a lot of those verbal
statements.
But did Iran take any actual actions
that hurt India?
Verbally K on multiple occasions
supported the so-called Kashmir Muslim
struggle and and whatever else you're
saying. These were all words. Please my
dear friends understand the difference
between words and actions.
Words
are meaningless.
always ignore words. Always focus solely
on actions. Did Iran take any actions
that in any way whatsoever hurt India?
Iran allowed India to use certain
terminals on the Chabahar port in order
to to support Afghanistan, the people of
Afghanistan. India and Iran worked
together to ensure that Armenia does not
get wiped out by Turkey and Azarbaijan.
India India supplied Armenia with
weapons, weapon systems, radars and so
many other things. All that was
transmitted through Iran. India Iran
worked together on this. There's a lot
of things India and Iran have done
together which have which has been
mutually beneficial.
Verbally Iran has done certain things
that India that Indians will find
upsetting and that's true. I have myself
said this that Kame has in the past
medddled in Kashmir verbally but has
Iran ever supplied arms ammunition money
to terrorists who who are fighting for
whatever in Kashmir Iran has never done
that. The Americans have done that the
Pakistanis have done that. Iran has
never done that. So please my point is I
don't disagree at all with you about
what you're saying. Kabini
said a bunch of things but he never did
a single thing that hurt India. That is
the difference. Now why did Kabini say
so and so so and so? because of his own
constituency, his own audience
also perhaps to support the Shia
population of Kashmir which was which
was being looked upon which is a
minority population in Kashmir who are
being portrayed as as collaborators
against
the so-called struggle of the Kashmiris
with India.
So for a variety of reasons certain
things are done and said but Iran has
never done something that hurts India.
Please also understand that.
Okay.
One question is about
uh Kulbush and Yadav. It looks like
there was some Iranian involvement in
what happened with Kulbushav. I'm not
100% sure about that. Also he seems to
have been kidnapped by Pakistanis from
Iranian territory.
Was there an explicit Iranian angle in
that or not? We don't we're not very
sure.
But overall overall Iran did nothing
substantial or nothing significant or
nothing actually that I can think of
that actually hurt India. Words are
words actions are what matter. Please
understand that
2 kow photography says my boy lives near
lives near the US naval base in Bahrain.
It's very stressful for us. The civilian
apartment hit was hardly a kilometer
from her from her house. Hope the war
ends soon. Yeah, I'm I'm I hope it ends
soon. I hope that there's no more, you
know, damage to civilian infrastructure.
I hope that nobody gets hurt. Civilian
civilians. No, no civilians get hurt.
War is terrible for civilians, right?
It's the civilians who suffer. It's
terrible. It's horrible for civilians.
So, I hope that your Bua remains safe.
I'm sorry to hear that she's in this
situation currently. Um but yeah, the
thing is that Iran is is targeting every
nation that hosts US military
installations and personnel.
That's the logic. It's a very clear
military logic and unfortunately this
can cause damage to civilian
infrastructure and perhaps hurt
civilians. So I hope it doesn't happen.
I hope the war ends soon. I completely
agree with you. I hope so.
Uh Han Sharma says on the verge of the
third world war, but at least we are in
the semi-finals.
That's why I did not do a live stream
yesterday because I was pretty sure
everybody will want to watch the India
West Indies match because in India, you
know, cricket is at the forefront of
everything. Yeah, I hope it's not the
verge of World War II. World War II, we
may be on the verge of World War II if
Russia and if Russia gets involved.
China will not get involved. They're too
scared. But Russia uh but yes, at least
we we're in the semi-finals.
Sen says, "Now that Pakistani leaders
have openly condemned the US government,
what are your thoughts on the future of
Pakistan US relations, can it be
advantageous to us?" So, let me once
again remind you all that words have no
meaning.
Only actions are are meaningful.
Pakistan will not take any action. It
will not raise one finger in a way that
will damage US interests or hurt US
interests. A few words, what does it
mean? It means nothing. Words are these
are thugway words.
Okay. The words are meaningless. The
prime minister of Pakistan Shabb Sharif
what did he say? Let's let's once again
revisit uh his tweet. Let's see. Okay.
Let's see. So Pakistan is a US. Okay,
understand that. So now here's the
tweet.
Um the government and people of Pakistan
join the people of Iran in their hour of
grief and sorrow and extend the most
sincere condolences on the martyrdom of
his imminence.
Pakistan also expresses concern about
the violation of the norms of
international law. It's an age-old
convention that the heads of states and
state of and government should not be
targeted and that sort of thing. So it's
an implicit indirect uh condemnation
of what the Americans and Israelis have
done. Right? So it's words. It's words.
Words have no meaning. Pakistan will not
do anything in any anything act any
actual action that will in any way
whatsoever
be damaging to the interests of the US
and Israel. Yeah. Pakistan US relations
are guaranteed to be fantastic. I
promise you that. I promise you that
this will not affect Pakistan US
relationship relations in any way
whatsoever.
Harish Sharma says you just tweeted that
there are six not five sovereign
nations. What prompted you to make the
change and is India still sovereign? Why
is everyone copying UNX? Why the US is
not flattening the whole of Iran as we
know they can? Okay, multiple questions
but uh once again what did I what did I
tweet once again? Let's go there. So
like I said a few minutes earlier. This
is what I tweeted. Okay. So yeah this is
my tweet. This is something you all are
very familiar with for a very long time.
I've been speaking about this for years.
My sovereignty framework there are only
six. So I it used to be five right?
Initially it was four then I revised it
to five and now today I have said it as
six because this is an evolving
situation. the world evolves and based
on the evolution of the world and how
things change this has to be changed. So
right now there are six sovereign
nations on earth the US, Russia, China,
India, Israel and Iran. Right? Every
other nation exists either as a
sovereign semi- sovereign state or as a
geopolitical vessel. That is what I
stated today and I've given my
explanation of why I have added Iran to
the list. Iran is fighting for survival
without Chinese or Russian support. It's
it's fighting on its own. It's fighting
for its survival. It's fighting for its
sovereignty. And that's why because of
what's happening right now, you have to
add Iran to the list. Iran is acting and
fighting as a genuinely sovereign nation
without anyone's substantial assistance.
That's why I have added to Iran to it.
Uh is India still sovereign? I will
revisit this in a month or so. Maybe
this list will change in a month.
Okay.
Maybe the number will may come down to
four possibly. We'll see about that.
Right now I'm keeping it at six. Right
now I'm not revisiting India's status as
a sovereign nation. In a month or so I
will revisit that.
It it may change. Uh why is the US not
flattening the whole of Iran? Because
even superpowers don't do such certain
things until they are desperate. Because
then even their allies will have no
option but to condemn them. If they
flatten the whole of Iran, it's going to
cause millions of deaths. Even their
allies, even the NATO nations, even the
EU nations, even the UK, even Japan,
even their vasals will have to condemn
that. That's why they're not doing that.
They want to achieve their military and
political objectives with as little
effort and as little damage as possible.
That's that's the reason why Kakashi
says, "Are the GCC nations? If so, more
than Japan, Korea or less? Why also why
some vasals are kept poor like Pakistan
and Nigeria but uh UAE and South Korea
are rich albeit corporate socialist
hellscapes.
Um so yeah vasalhood also has degrees of
vasalhood.
Okay, some nations are like 100% vasal,
some nations are like 33% vasals. So, so
if you look at France for example, I
would say it is a quasi sovereign
nation, maybe 70% sovereign, but the 30%
is a problem. It's a huge problem. So,
there are degrees of vasal. Okay. Uh the
Gulf Cooperation Council nations are the
vasals. Well, you have American bases on
their territory,
right? And they can't do a thing that
goes against American interests or or or
dictats that makes them vasiles. Um,
are the GCC nations more vasal vasalized
than, for example, Japan or Korea? No,
they're less vasalized because Japan and
Korea are under permanent full-scale
military occupation. There's more than
130 American military bases in on
Japanese territory. Permanent US
military bases on Korea must be around
at least 100. South Korea, GCC, each
nation may have two, three maybe or
maybe just one. So definitely the degree
of vasilization is less but they are
still vasiles. You understand? So yeah
you can do do a very granular study of
this granular granular analysis of this
and you will find that the degree of
fossilization is is different for each
nation. Why are some vasals kept poor
and some kept rich? Yeah it depends on
the on on what those nations are being
used for.
Some nations who are viles are used as
cannon foder.
Some nations if you keep them poor and
keep them divided it's more favorable to
you. So Pakistan is just a stick to beat
India with right
the US doesn't Pakistan's see it depends
on the quality of the population also
Pakistan's population is not such that
it can produce high quality research and
technology and all. So why why make the
nation rich? It's a huge investment of
time effort all that to make a nation
rich. Pakistan serves American purposes
exactly the way it is. Why why try and
elevate it,
right? In the case of uh Korea, South
Korea, it was very different. So each
nation is different and that's why you
have different uh uh you know u ways the
US deals with them. So Nigeria again
Nigeria is just a big source of oil.
That's why it's kept vasalized.
Otherwise the US has no interest in in
anything about Nigeria. That's how it
is. Assant says, uh, you have inspired
me to make a video on Indian
sociogenetic history. When I release it,
I earnestly invite you to watch and
debate it. Thank you. Certainly,
certainly. I'm so glad that you are
doing that. Please go ahead and make the
video once it's out. Do let me know and
I shall certainly watch it and uh
possibly debate it. All right. Saga
Savant say, "Okay, Sagar Sav, thank you
very much, sir. Thank you very much
indeed." Here's Manticor says I think
they want to partition Iran, East Iran
and West Iran. A more dangerous and
volatile history. Ironically, the
government government of Iran India will
pivot back to Russian oil. The
government of India is currently in the
process of pivoting very rapidly to to
Russian oil. Right? That's happening
right now. India's Indian refineries are
going back to purchasing Russian oil.
Now, when it comes to Iran, that's a
very interesting point to raise and I
spoke about this a few minutes ago. My
point is they don't want to partition
Iran into east and west. They want to
ideally balconize Iran into multiple
pieces. Okay. So let's let's uh let me
illustrate
my point by looking at this. Okay. Let's
see
uh major ethnic
groups
in Iran.
So when you balkanize a country you b
you do it based on ethnicity based on
ethnic groups. Let's take this for
example. You see there are a bunch of
people a bunch of ethnic groups in Iran.
The Baloi, the Arabs, the lurs, the
Kurs, the Turks and the Persians.
So balkcanization is done along these
ethnic and linguistic lines.
Okay. So the Americans ideally they they
will never state it openly but they
actually probably have this as the end
goal. The bulcanization of Iran, break
India, break Iran's
That was a Freudian slave. Was it break
Iran into multiple countries, multiple
independent countries who may fight each
other, but the Americans will deal with
each of these countries individually.
And some some of these regions are big
oil producers and those will be the ones
that the Americans are genuinely
interested in. The objective is to
balconize Iran. And for that, you don't
have to put boots on the ground.
Possibly if you can create sufficient
chaos in the country, the country
disintegrates.
Especially if it is multiple ethnic
groups with histories of their own. In
that case, all you have to do is
completely destroy the country in the in
the sense that destroy the government.
Uh
sow chaos in the country like high
degree of chaos and then the country
just fragments. That is a very viable
potentially potentially viable uh you
know potential end goal for the US in
this military operation.
Vir Kamak says I was born in Bahrain and
I lived in Bahrain. My family still
lives there. They have no way to leave
because all the nearby airports are
closed right now and I also cannot go
there. Can Iran target civilians?
Iran will most likely not target
civilians?
Most likely they will not.
um at least in in these GCCG countries
in the in the uh they may target
civilians perhaps I'm saying perhaps in
Israel perhaps
they've gone after several hotels right
in some of these countries those hotels
allegedly were were housing American
troops or American officials or
personnel so that's the that's possibly
the military justification for targeting
hotels. Um, but I don't think Iran will
go after civilian centers or or civilian
populations. It it makes no sense from a
military perspective. Iran also will
have a finite number of drones and
missiles and they will not want to waste
those drones on and missiles on
non-military targets and non-strategic
targets. So, from a purely logical
perspective, it makes no sense to target
civilians when you're fighting for your
survival. So I am pretty optimistic that
Iran will not go after civilians. So
yeah. So I'm sorry that the situation
exists and your family is is they cannot
leave the country right now. All the
airports that are closed obviously they
are closed. Uh let's take so but but I
hope things get better. Right. Let's
take a look at what is the airspace
situation.
We will go to um yeah give me a second.
Let me see the airspace situation over
West Asia right now. Um, we're looking
at India. Let's zoom out. Let's zoom
out. Let's zoom out. What is happening?
So, as you can see, there's no aircraft
flying over Iran.
Uh, there are no aircraft flying over
Iraq either.
Uh, nothing over Iraq, nothing over
Iraq, nothing over Syria, nothing over
Jordan, nothing over Israel also right
now. So, looks like all the Israeli
airports are mostly closed. What is this
thing doing here? This aircraft, where
did it come from? From Lebanon. Okay.
From Beirut. What about this aircraft?
Belgrade to Tel Aiv. Well, they are
pretty brave. Ah, it's not a civilian
aircraft. Maybe some kind of other type
of aircraft which is definitely very
it's a cargo aircraft of some kind. It's
coming from Belgrade. That's also really
interesting. Okay. So that is Belgrade
to Tel Aviv. Uh what is this aircraft
doing here? Where did it come from? From
Aman. Okay. So there's one aircraft that
took off from Aman. It's going to
Istanbul.
Um there are aircraft flying over the
Arabian Peninsula. There are aircraft uh
flying over well the mom. So are these
civilian aircraft? What kind of aircraft
are these? This is definitely a civilian
aircraft. Uh Qatar nothing is happening.
Uh there are drones and whatnot flying
over KQatar but nothing else. Abu Dhabi,
Dubai are closed. Sharah is closed. Oman
is fine. So yeah, that's the situation
right now and that makes sense right
now. Nobody will want to fly over these
regions. Everyone's staying away. You
have aircraft flying over Armenia,
Aarbajan, Turkmanistan, Afghanistan,
Pakistan,
right?
This is an interesting whatever. Okay.
Oh, that's interesting.
This obviously is S Petersburg. Okay.
So, let's not uh I could do this all
day, but the point is yeah, there's this
airspace closure situation right now.
Yeah.
MK says, "Are we choosing Basalhood
through Israel as Rajnat Singh prayed at
the wailing wall? Modi's visit to Israel
night right before the war, Israel, UAE,
India partnership,
we have taken a side. We have chosen a
side in this war.
When it comes to vasalhood,
it's more if if India if India does
become a vasal, I will I will I will
reanalyze this in a month's time after
this war is over hopefully soon. I will
re reanalyze India's situation and
position.
And if India is found by me to actually
now be a vasal of some country, it will
not be Israel, it will be it'll be the
US.
Uh praying at veiling wall and all those
are symbolic gestures. It doesn't
necessarily mean anything.
See Hindus can pray to any god. Hindus
are by by nature a very respectful
people. Wherever they go they'll pray.
So if the defense minister prayed at the
wailing wall, it doesn't necessarily
mean that we are of Mr. Modi visited
Israel right before the war. That is an
interesting development. That's a very
interesting development. But um so I
will reanalyze the situation from
India's perspective once this war is
over. Right now I am categorizing India
as a fully as a fully sovereign nation
as of now.
NJ says could India take advantage of a
weakened Iran and demand greater
autonomy or a military base in Chabahar
or maneuver for other advantages. India
will be well advised to stay out of all
such uh things. Stay out of it
completely.
Um India should not ask for a military
base in Chabahar or whatsoever. Let the
war first end. Iran is not weakened.
Iran is fighting off multiple nations at
the same time. Don't take Iran light
lightly. Uh once the war ends, we can
see what situation Iran is in.
Uh but look
military base in Chabahar.
What about the intervening region which
is Pakistan temporarily? So no, India
should not do any of these things. It is
it is not advisable at all. Sager Savant
says for effective regime change a
ground invasion is required absolutely
which Trump may not have support by his
own people. So what can be the effective
conclusion? The effective conclusion is
that the US wants to very badly weaken
and damage Iran and create enough chaos
in Iran for Iran to disintegrate and
become balkcanized.
And then over time the parts of Iran
where which are rich in oil and gas
those the Americans would like to take
over directly or indirectly not directly
but indirectly.
For example a great example is Syria.
The Americans caused the civil war in
Syria for 10 for more than 10 years.
Al-Qaeda, ISIS, these are all American
proxies. Eventually, Syria was so badly
destabilized that eventually ISIS was
was able to succe succeed and the
Americans then recognized uh that ISIS
terrorist as the president of Syria and
now they're doing business with him. So,
the Americans would like to do something
similar with Iran most likely
balkcanizing Iran, fragment Iran and
then deal with each of these fragments
individually. That is my conclusion.
Aries manticor says I understand your
frustration with the government of India
but their collective stubborn behavior
has surprised everyone and us hopefully
us Indians too.
Um
yeah I mean my frustration is more of a
frustration with the US with the
government of India not reforming the
institutions and doing the reforms which
take long time to to implement and from
my perspective this process should have
started like 12 years ago even now
nothing is being done. So that is what
frustrates me. Yeah.
Um yeah and hopefully if the people
understand that this is required that
these steps and measures are necessary
and if we can all voice our opinion and
hopefully then put some kind of uh well
if you want to call it pressure then
pressure on the government that you know
your voters want these things then maybe
they'll do it.
XZP has become a new member. Thank you
very much sir or ma'am and welcome to
the channel's membership. Thank you.
Vijay Viki says, "If war goes on for a
long time, can propping up proxies
weaken Iran?" That's definitely a
legitimate uh tool in a regime change
toolbox. Proing propping up propping up
proxies. If Iran is destabilized, you
could have al-Qaeda or ISIS terrorists
enter Iran from the northwest of Iran
and start creating havoc, right? and
then take over some parts of the country
and become a proxy of US or Israel or
whatever you know that sort of thing can
certainly happen and that will
definitely weaken Iran if this sort of
thing successfully is implemented right
Koma's mindset says is it possible that
India picked aside this early because it
plans to export weapons like air defense
of Brahmos after a successful operation
Sindur what are my thoughts no thoughts
India has picked aside early because it
has it had no choice. It's not doing
India is not doing this because we have
plans to export things for India also
it's a matter of survival for India also
it is a matter of survival okay that's
what it is
yeah Iran is fighting for its survival
in one way through military means India
is fighting for its survival in a bunch
of other ways and that's why India has
picked a side it's nothing to do with
exports of weapons or operations in duro
whatever not the
Uh Adi Prahan says Superbase and
Firebase have been stopped. Drooting
started really fascinating. Let's see.
Let's see.
Uh Superbase
is it not available in India?
I
see that it's available. I suppose you
could sign in or start your project or
whatever. Looks like it's available in
India but I have not tried to use it so
I I don't know what about Firebase.
So the the URLs aren't blocked at least.
Get started. Get 300 bucks to unlock all
Firebase features.
Firebase and generative AI.
Well, looks like it's still there, but
I'm not sure. Um sign in or whatever. So
I don't know. I I was not aware of the
any issues with superb or firebase
drooing started. I'm not sure can't say
can't say I'm not aware I I'll have to
look into that. Look into that.
Bipoling says, "Do you think Trump
miscalculated as regime change seems
unlikely?"
It's it's possible that the ultimate
objective of the US is not to uh see
whoever many people are saying that
rightfully saying correctly saying like
I've also said that regime change is
impossible without boots on the ground.
Impossible. But what's possible is the
bulcanization of Iran. weaken Iran
enough and create enough chaos in the
country that the country just fragments.
Maybe that is the actual objective, the
balconization of Iran.
So if that's the objective, then the
thing hasn't been a miscalculation thus
far. Obviously, I'm pretty certain the
Americans and Israelis are kind of
surprised by the Iranian response thus
far, right? It's been a very robust
response and they have come up with
innovations that have definitely taken
the world by surprise. I mean those
fragmentation clusters or those those u
um
those hypersonic missiles
they are deploying a bunch of you know
decoys 25 decoys or so that all mimic
the uh the characteristics of of of
missiles and that's why the interceptors
are not working properly and once the
the the cluster of decoys is is deployed
the warhead suddenly acquire the the the
the warhead or the vehicle associated
with the warhead suddenly acquires
hypersonic velocity. So many innovations
you're seeing right now that Iran has
come up with and that's definitely
surprising. So there could be some
element of miscalculation for sure.
That's an element of being caught by
surprise also possibly the US and Israel
and they both said both nations said
that they are after regime change. Yeah.
So
General Subutai says Iran being the most
sanctioned yet producing worldclass
drones. What is stopping India? I have
no idea what is stopping India.
This war makes us calculated defeat is
possible
or or
for India or it's complicated.
So why okay first of all you the
question is what is stopping India? I
have no idea what's stopping India.
India just has has mediocre standards.
The government of India and everything
else the whole system is geared for
mediocrity. The people of India they are
excellent people.
I mean look at the people who are
running the tech sector and other
sectors in the US. The best people are
Indians.
So there's nothing wrong with Indians.
Indians are some of the most brilliant
people on the surface of the planet. The
problem is the system, the government,
the institutions and the education
system and everything. It is geared for
mediocrity. It is geared for the lowest
of standards. Every generation the
standards are lowered. That's an issue
in India. the procurement processes, the
bureaucratic delays, the red tape, this
that everything ensures that everything
happens at a glacial pace, slow pace
and look at the salaries that engineers
get. If you are in a government
organization like DRD or ISRO, whatever
I mean who's going to be motivated to
work so these are the problems in India
very frustrating.
Um, that's what's stopping India. India
India system is stopping India. This war
makes US calculated defeat is possible
for India. I'm not sure what you're
asking there, sir. Not sure about that.
But hopefully I've answered your first
question. Mi says, "I live in the US and
Iran employing a scorched earth
strategy. Has Israelis geeked out here?
Do you think that nukes might be used?
Also, was right. Was India right in
pulling out of Iran Chabahar port given
the situation?" Let me answer the second
part first. Was India right in pulling
out of Iran Chabahar port given the
situation?
India pulled out of Chabahar a few weeks
before this went down. Right? Let's
quickly fact check that.
Uh
when did India
pull
out of Jahar
scaling back not complete this India had
already transferred its full committed
amount of 120 million to Iran by late
fulfilling its obligations. So
essentially India pulled out by late
2025. Okay, that's the deal. All the
other stuff is is is doesn't matter.
India liquidated its its uh stake in
Chabahar.
India liquidated its stake in Chabahar
in late 2025 by paying $120 million to
Iran. So that's when India pulled out.
That is
late 2025. So let's say it happened in
December, December, January, February.
So it's like almost 3 months before the
war happened, right? Why did India do
this? Because the Americans were
reimposing sanctions. That's one excuse.
That's that's that's one explanation.
Another explanation is that India would
have perhaps had some inkling of what
was going to happen.
So uh was India right in doing this? I
suppose it was right. India had no
choice. If India doesn't pull out, then
it gets sanctioned
and whatever stake it has get destroy
gets destroyed with American or Israeli
air strikes. So I suppose India had no
choice. Weak nations don't have too many
choice right now. Um Iran employing a
scorched earth strategy has Israelis
geeked out. They think that nukes might
be used. I think nukes for from Iran's
perspective are a matter of are a matter
of last resort. We don't even know if
the Iranians have nukes. I am pretty
certain that Iran has sufficient file
material to quickly, you know, produce a
bunch of nukes, maybe 5, 10 nukes, you
know, uh, tactical yield warheads. I'm
pretty sure they have that much file
material, highly enriched uranium. I'm
pretty sure they have it. Until now,
they did not ever announce that they
they did not ever test a nuclear weapon,
but I'm sure they can put one together
quickly. It's not that difficult from a
from an engineering perspective, right?
Um, but Iran won't do this unless it's a
do or die thing, unless they have
nothing left to lose anymore. So, I
don't think Iran will use nukes,
un in case you're saying Israel may use
nukes or the US may use nukes, but that
is slightly higher on the on the scale
of possibilities and depending on how
things go in let's say a week's time or
so. If Iran is still fighting away, is
still fighting and if they are causing
significant damage, especially on
Israel, then such things may be thought
of by the Americans and the Israelis
because Israel does have uh a decent
number of warheads and the US obviously
we know, right? Yeah. Okay.
Vishal Ro says India took a side here
but remains overall neutral. No, India
is not neutral. Okay. You have you're
giving proof. Deep France ties 150 plus
Rafal sixth generation talks. That's
talks. Russia deals A and I posted five
minutes ago about five new S400
squadrons and talks. See talk. I don't
give a damn about talks unless until a
deal is signed and things get
operational. I don't care. Talk talk
talk is fine. Talk talk. Let's see. Uh
ANI
AI Twitter.
Let's see what AI Twitter has to say.
No, let's not. One second. I actually
have an actual thing going. Um, okay.
Let us go to the actual Twitter
homepage.
Okay. And um, let's see. AI. Do we have
A and I? How many? No. AI.
A and I. What does A and I have to say?
Let's see.
Um, 5 minutes ago, you say? Let's see.
must be earlier.
You're saying that A and I posted 5
minutes ago about S400's.
Um, it'll definitely be more than 5
minutes ago. What about
S400?
Latest.
Let's see.
Uh, is it S-en 400?
No.
Okay. I'm not sure about that. What's
going on? I'll not waste your your time
by digging digging for all that. France,
listen, India took a side here, but
remains overall neutral. India is not
neutral. India is multi-aligned. India's
policy has been that of multi-alignment,
not neutrality.
When you have deep ties with France, we
are aligned with France in a multiple in
a number of ways. When we are doing
things with Russia, we align with Russia
also. This is called multi-alignment. It
is not called neutrality.
Multi-alignment is very very different
from neutrality.
But in this war, what side has India
taken? It's not a neutral side. India
has clearly sided with Israel in the US.
So it is not neutrality.
Fast snail says it's the first time in
47 years the US and Israel are trying
regime change in Thran. If yes, is it
too little too late? Also I am
am I the only one thinking that Israel
is using the west?
So yes for for the first time in 47 the
Americans and Israelis are trying are
attempting a regime change in Thran.
Is it too little too late? Nothing is
too little too late. If they succeed
here they they get what they want.
So and it's not like they lost they've
they've lost a lot because they've
waited this long. It's not the case. So
it's not too little too late. If they
succeed now, it's going to be a big
success, big victory for them. Whether
it is a regime change or balkcanization,
both will be big victories for the US
and Israel.
Uh, is Israel using the West or is the
West using Israel? That's always a big
question. I'm not sure.
Kushagra Singh says, "Is there any
opportunity for India in this?" No,
there's no opportunity for India in
this.
Saga Gare says by Amisha. Can anyone ask
how China defense system failed in Iran?
Did India did Iran have Chinese radars
or whatever? Chinese defense systems?
I'm not sure. I've not looked into that
angle. Let's see. Um
does Iran operate
Chinese radars? Let's see. China has
deployed the YC etc. to detect. So,
okay.
So, it has some Chinese radars, Chinese
u uh military equipment. Let's see.
Air defense assets and so on. Chinese
systems uh HQ16, HQ17 AE. What are these
two things? Let's find out. HQ16, HQ7.
Are these radars? Okay. Surface air
missile systems and so on. So it doesn't
look like Iran uses a lot of Chinese
systems. Uh the Chinese system they we
saw was a radar that kind of detects
stealth aircraft.
So has it failed? Has it not failed? I'm
not 100% sure. Looks like
looks like it may not have worked
perfectly or whatever. I'm not sure.
I've not looked into it in detail. It
looks like there are some systems that
the Iranians are using. So possibly some
of them may not have uh successfully
done their job.
Abishek Kirbast says India always chose
Israel over Iran. It's not a big deal.
Okay sir. Thank you very much. Meshov
says 15 if India becomes US God forbid.
Would it be more kind of a Pakistan kind
or Japan kind with respect to daily life
development etc. It will not be a
Pakistan kind of vasalhood. It will not
be a Japan kind of vasalhood. It will be
a India kind of vasalhood.
So what will happen if India becomes the
US vasal? India will become a huge
market that the Americans will export to
and
make money as a consequence. That will
be one thing. Second thing, the
government of India will essentially be
run by the American AIS and everything.
So which means that the US gets complete
granular micromanagement support uh
micro managerial level control over
everything India does daily life daily
life will go on as as it is most people
will never know that things have changed
completely development it will go on in
the same way it's happening right now
the Americans don't want India to become
a 15 20 trillion economy they want India
to remain a four 5 trillion economy so
so India's GDP will keep growing at 5%
6% per year Nothing will change majorly.
There will be no major reforms. India
will remain a mediocre nation and so on.
So that is the kind of vashood you will
have for the ordinary person. They will
never possibly even realize that you are
a vasal of another country. Nothing will
actually change on the surface.
Aris Manticor says the cards have been
stacked against us the past 2,000 years,
past 1,000 years actually, but we
survived. The cards were stacked in the
past 15 years, but we have clawed to
this state. We will endure in a manner
most absurd.
We have a 10,000 plus year old history.
And so if something goes wrong for for a
few years, it doesn't matter. We will
eventually long-term hopefully prevail
and and get stronger. So let us be
positive, optimistic, let's not be all
gloom and doom. Even if we are a we
become a vasal state for a few years,
we'll find a way out. So let's be
positive.
Vijay Viki says one of Indian crony
recently met Hillary Clinton. Her
foundation was responsible for the
propping up of Muhammad Inos. What are
your thoughts? Indian crony. I'm not
sure who this Indian crony is. Are you
talking about some kind of uh
uh business person or whatever? I'm not
sure who you're talking about. But look,
let's say you are a business person.
Let's say you are an industrialist or
whatever. It makes sense to be connected
with various very powerful people. Uh
you know, Hillary Clinton is a very
powerful person and very relevant person
even today. So yeah, it makes sense
and as long as you're not breaking
India's laws or whatever, as long as the
government of India is not opposed to
it, you'll do it. You'll do it. Uh so
that those are my thoughts or whoever it
is, I don't know who it is.
Okay. Black Panther says will join NATO
in this war. UK and Francebased attack.
I am not sure if any UK or France. Okay.
Um
has Iran targeted
any UK or French uh military
installations
or bases.
Um, yeah, I'm not getting anything
news
European
Accroeri. Okay, Cyprus. That's
interesting. British bas in Cypress. I'm
not sure about French bases or whatever.
Uh, I don't think NATO will join the
war. I don't think so. Uh, it is
unlikely at this stage at least. Yeah,
at this st at this stage it is unlikely.
Tarun says any game plan for India to
come out of these situations of V
wasalhood there must be a way I feel bad
to work in IT at the cost of the country
sovereignty. Don't blame yourself if
you're working in in it. You are
actually contributing to India's GDP.
So you don't need to there's no reason
for you to feel bad personally.
Um any game plan for India to come out
of this situation of V was out? Well,
that's for the government to do and if
there is a genuine game game plan that
can help India, I better not speak about
it over here. Don't you think? Yeah, I
should not discuss it over here openly.
In in case there's a game plan,
there must be a way.
Prattana says, I was referring to Nupour
Sharma fiasco in divine justice. Arabs
provoked riots and killings, especially
Qatar.
Okay. Okay. Okay. Nupur Sharma thing.
Okay. Okay, that's a matter of Indian
politics, internal politics, something
that I never discuss.
So, okay, I I don't discuss Indian
politics as you know.
Aris Manticor says, "Will Iran be forced
to use the dirty bomb strategy?" I hope
not. I hope not. What's a dirty bomb? In
for for those who may not know a dirty
bomb is a bomb that has a conventional
chemical explosive like your standard
bombs but it also has nuclear material.
So when the bomb explodes the nuclear
material is dispersed
and causes radiation fallout fallout
over a wide area. That's a dirty bomb.
So that is something Iran can Iran
definitely has plenty of file material
which may not perhaps be weapons grade
but it's definitely uranium right
235 possibly I don't know about
plutonium but 235 they they will
probably have so that can be used for a
dirty bomb I hope Iran doesn't have to
use it and I hope that well that's a
very nasty thing to do actually but yeah
when you're desperate you may some
people may do it so I hope it doesn't
happen
part Shivas says Any message for ayata
lovers crying in India? I have no no
such messages. No no no comments.
DT says you are my first geopolitics
tutor. Thank you sir. Thank you so much
for your very kind words and I yeah
thank you so much.
Mkeshv says please explain terms vasal
protectorate ally and trustee.
I don't know what trustees are. That's
not that's not a geopolitical term as
far as I know. I don't use that. Ally
means you have a treaty, a clearly
defined treaty which you've signed which
which lays out the rules and
responsibilities. Protector it means
you're a weak nation protected by a by a
more powerful nation which is like a
vasal. A vasal which can be a vasal but
not necessarily always. A vasal is a
nation that is weak that is controlled
by a more powerful. So this is a weak
nation who is controlled by a more
powerful nation and exploited by a more
powerful nation in in certain ways or a
variety of ways or always that's a
escape
escape something. Uh yes I'm doing very
well. Thank you very much sir. You have
got five questions. First since the ayat
is dead what is your reaction first of
all? uh tragic and and
well highly unusual for a world leader
to be assassinated. Uh definitely is a
blatant and flagrant violation of
international law. Yeah, that's my
reaction.
Second, okay, for do you think first is
it a boon for the world since he's dead
now? No.
What were his views on India and your
views on the ayatah? Look my views on
the I have no views about his religious
thing or whatever. His views on India
were well he expressed certain views
about India. He kind of at certain times
supported the uh Kashmir freedom thing
or what the alleged Kashmir thing and so
on. But overall his actions towards
India were never hurtful towards India.
Words and actions are very different
things. My point is ignore the words and
look at the actions. under his
leadership, Iran never took any actions
that were hurtful towards India. His
views to on India, his words that he
sometimes spoke may have been annoying
for for a lot of Indians obviously, but
his actions were never anti-India.
Next, um do you think an attack on the
EU or Turkey is imminent even though
Turkey as far as I understand it is
somewhere in the middle regarding Iran?
Uh Turkey hosts
American nuclear weapons. Turkey hosts
American uh military bases, American
personnel. Uh Turkey may have said some
nice words and send control of this
about Iran, but overall they're on
America's side. Turkey is not in the
middle. Turkey is not in the middle.
Turkey is squarely in America's side.
Uh so is an attack on the EU or Turkey
imminent? I think it is not imminent.
um
unless
American planes take off from Turkey to
attack Iran or something in that case
something could happen. So EU is
probably not imminent. Turkey also most
likely not imminent right now.
Mahesh Karnan says why Iran has not
attacked Turkey and Pakistan. There are
reports that Netanyahu's office was hit
by Iran. Even I heard that Netanyahu's
office was targeted by Iran. Let's see.
Uh Nathan Yahoo office.
Let's see. We here Nathan Yahoo's office
targeted insurprise attacks
and there's some factchecking and so on
and so forth. Uh so they're saying that
Iran has claimed this but they're not
saying that this actually happened. Uh
so yeah, Nathan's office apparently was
targeted by Iran. That's what the
Iranian Iranians are claiming. Why has
Iran not target attacked Turkey and
Pakistan? See, first of all, Turkey is
very far away and Turkey is probably not
directly involved in this war in the
sense that I don't think there are
American aircraft taking off from Turkey
to attack Iran. So that's why Turkey
thus far has not been attacked. Pakistan
um maybe Iran doesn't want to fight too
many nations at the same time. Pakistan
is a very powerful military, not
compared to India, but compared to Iran,
maybe head-to-head possibly. Yeah, of
course Pakistan is currently facing a
war with Afghanistan.
Um, so yeah, right now Pakistan Iran
will not open a military front with
Pakistan right now. They know that
Pakistani airspace is being used by
Americans. They know that. They know
that Pakistan is actually an enemy of
Iran. They know that too. But right now
it doesn't make sense to fight three
major powers at the same time.
Israel, US and Pakistan. Why am I saying
Pakistan is a major power? Because
regionally it's a major power. Iran is
also Israel is also regionally a major
power and the US is a global superpower
but regionally it's got this massive
military force that it has piled up in
this region. So the US is a major power
here. Then Pakistan it is territory is
right there. So because of proximity
Pakistan becomes a major power. So Iran
doesn't it doesn't make sense for Iran
to fight everybody at the same time.
That's the mistake that Adolf Hitler did
right made. He tried to fight everybody
at the same time and that led to
Germany's destruction eventually. So it
doesn't make sense for Iran to start a
fight with everybody at the same time.
Makes no sense.
Paris is manticor says can a balconized
Iran go nuclear in a North Korea fashion
but it allows US to take part of its
territory for pragmatic regime survival
strategy. Yeah, it can happen. So let's
say Iran loses half of its territory
gets bulcanized. the non-Persian
territories become, you know, separate
entities. Iran could still survive in in
a broken down form, in a reduced form,
and it could at that time also possibly
go nuclear. It's possible. It's
possible. Yeah, it's also a possibility.
Mesh says, would the world be a better
place if Breton Woods had never been
scrapped in 71? How would India fare?
But 1857 resulted in an Indian victory.
How different would be the geopolitical
landscape be today? Look, it's all ifs
and buts. You can paint all kinds of
scenarios.
If 87 in 1857, if we had won, we may
have become a great superpower. We may
have become a great cultural nation. Who
knows a first world country. All kinds
of possibilities exist. But I can tell
you for sure if 18 1857 we had won then
India would be in a much better shape
today. India would not be this weird
secularized stupid nation. India would
be a much greater nation. India would
still be a proper full-fledged
civilization state which it is not
today. Uh and geopolitically obviously
the world would be different in that
case. Um if Britain votes had not been
scrapped in 71 how would India fare?
There are also once again there are like
500 different possibilities open out
there. I don't know even if Bretton
Woods had not been scrapped the global
system would still have been uh
controlled by the US. So I don't think
India would fare very differently in
that case at least possibly.
Prataradana says Iran war
show US won't be able to defeat China.
The sheer number of stealth jets,
hypersonics, stealth drones, nukes, US
bases will be gone in minutes. I
actually disagree.
I disagree.
There's 130 plus US bases in Japan, more
than 100 American bases in Korea. That's
230 at least. Then there is Taiwan,
which is a fortress island. Then there
is Guam. The US has way more force
deployed around China.
than what they have deployed against
Iran right now.
I think the US will devastate China.
China stealth jets and all. Okay, it's
nice on paper, but have they been ever
tested in a war?
If the US and China go to war, the US
will devastate China. That's why China
is so careful. So careful. Yeah.
And see, China doesn't have the risk
appetite that Iran has. It's a very
different nation. China, they don't have
any appetite for risk. Iran has a
totally different appetite for risk.
They right now they are fighting this
war which could end in their complete
destruction. But they are determined to
go on fighting if if required, but they
will not surrender. That's a different
mindset. China doesn't have this
mindset. It's a very different mindset.
So I think if there's a war between the
US and China, the US will devastate
China.
Thus Nike says, "You have become my role
model in a short time." Thank you very
much, sir. Thank you very much indeed. I
also want to become secure, confident
and knowledgeable like you. I hope you
do. Work on yourself. Work on improving
yourself. Work on becoming more skilled,
right? And work on work on raising your
standards slowly, gradually. Everybody
does. That way you become more
confident, you become more secure.
Right? So all the best sir. I'm I'm I'm
very grateful to you for your very kind
words. Now the question is is US and
Israel attack proactive or did they not
have any choice but to attack? They had
the choice to not attack. They decided
to attack. This was very proactive.
Okay.
Many people could argue that there was
no need for them to attack. There was no
need to go after Iran. Many people could
argue that way also. So this was a
decision that was
made and then the attack happened. It's
very proactive.
Soilent
blue yellow green soilent says is
Pakistan Afghanistan attack or USRussia
power move P balance.
Is it the USRussia power move?
No,
we know that the Americans want Bagram.
Maybe the Pakistanis provoke Afghanistan
by launching air strikes on civilians to
destabilize Afghanistan and possibly
eventually the situation ends with
America taking Bram again. That's a
far-fetched but plausible uh
possibility. So one one should take that
possibility seriously. But uh
but overall there are very
legitimate grievances that the Afghans
have with respect to Pakistan
and I'm not sure how involved Russia is
in this matter.
So you could probably you would probably
be correct to see this as a as a
regional issue. Two nations hating each
other. The Pakistanis we know they hate
the Afghans. The Afghans they hate back
the Pakistanis even more. and the
Pakistanis are squatting on Afghan
territory. So, and the Pakistanis they
have this sense of superiority that we
can strike you at will, we can kill your
civilians. So, that's that's what
happened. It's not really a USRussia
power move at least
if you see it superficially, I suppose.
Goam says, isn't it good for the rest of
the world if the war prolongs and the US
economy gets hit significantly and can't
dominate other countries anymore?
The longer this war continues,
the more India and China and Iran and
and and and Japan
will be impacted.
This will not impact the US economy that
much.
See, right now the straight of Hormuz
has been closed. It's closed.
That's because of that there is no oil
flowing from West Asia into India or
China or Japan.
Because of this, oil prices will shoot
up maybe $150 a barrel.
If that continues, your the prices of
your sugar and tomatoes and potatoes and
everything will shoot up.
This is going to impact India badly.
Also China it won't impact the US that
much you understand it's it's not good
for the rest of the world world it's
terrible for the rest of the world
says J Mir Shimemer says Iraq war was
also for Netanyahu
okay Iraq war you mean the 2003 war
okay I'm not sure not sure
uh yeah Dr. Dr. John Mir Shimemer he is
a very very senior respected experienced
analyst. So maybe one should take what
he says seriously. Maybe his predictions
I don't know always true but that's fine
but the analysis definitely is valuable.
So I will think about it. I look into
it. Yeah I look into it from that
perspective but I haven't thought about
this matter. So Ranav says very
informative channel. Thank you very much
sir. Thank you so much.
Vipin Vihari has become a new member.
Thank you very much Ven G. Welcome to
the channel's membership. Thank you.
Escape
Escapus
Duras says as they have nothing. Okay,
this is a continuation of an earlier
stream of questions. As they have
nothing to lose now, I believe that
they're going to extinguish their
missile reserves. Iran.
Oh, we'll see about that.
Um,
is the GCC concerned about their
security after Iranian strikes shattered
their reputation for safety? Will they
pivot towards neutral power, stay with
the US or raise this privately?
Privately, they'll be very upset that
the Americans are not taking care of
their defense.
The Americans seem to be concerned only
about Israel's defense. See, what was
the deal between the US and the GCC
nations? The deal was that the US will
sell huge amounts of arms and ammunition
to these countries, military equipment,
billions of dollars worth. That's number
one. Number two, the US will install
military bases in these countries and
these nations will allow it. And in
exchange for all of that, the US will
guarantee their security.
And if somebody attacks those nations,
the US will retaliate and ensure that
these nations security is taken care of.
That was the deal.
That's why you have places like Dubai
coming up
under the US security umbrella. But now
see what's happening. Iran is hitting
these nations and the Americans haven't
been able to stop that.
So privately these nations will be very
upset. They'll be very upset that one
the US was not able to stop this and
it's not currently being able to stop
Iranian attacks. And secondly, they may
also feel perhaps that the Americans are
not taking this seriously enough.
They'll feel perhaps the Americans are
not taking these nations defense
seriously enough.
So yes, the GCC will be very concerned,
very concerned. And maybe they are right
to feel concerned and maybe they are
right to have this grievance against the
United States.
They may be right to I if they feel that
the Americans are prioritizing Iraq Is
Israel's defense more than the GCC
nation's defense. They may be right in
the in feeling that way. So will they
pivot towards neutral powers, stay with
the US or raise this privately.
They'll be able to pivot nowhere.
Okay.
They'll be they'll be able to pivot
nowhere.
The Americans won't allow them to pivot
anywhere.
won't work. The US is too powerful.
Okay. Uh since you began posting, I have
been enlightened on countless matters.
Thank you for sharing your vast
knowledge. Please keep educating us.
Thank you very much, sir. I certainly
will. I have I shall keep this going.
The Ask a Bijit Show. Absolutely. Thank
you very much, sir. Thank you so much.
Abishek Singh says, "Why Indians on X
full support us and Israel Sar?" Well,
that's what Indians do. I don't know
why, but they do. See, I have nothing
against supporting this nation, that
nation, whatever. But support your
nation first and have self some
selfrespect.
Yeah. But yes, Indians are enamored with
certain nations. I am not saying don't
be enamored with certain nations. My
point is have some dignity and
selfrespect.
Yeah.
Krishna says, "Is Kab really dead or in
hideout with nentity?"
I don't know what new entity is but uh
about Kame's death I don't think he's
hiding somewhere at the age of 86 why
why would he want to go and hide
somewhere
the other thing about Kame's death is
this
he was killed in his house
in his residence
the the Americans or Israelis or whoever
one of these two they knew where Kame's
residence was and they they launched a
strike on his residence which killed to
Kame and some family me members.
So it's not like Kame did not know this
was coming. Kame knew that a war is
imminent that American and Israeli
strikes are imminent
and he I am sure had the option to go
and hide somewhere in a secure location
in a bunker or whatever.
But Kam chose to stay in his house.
Now why did he do that? It means certain
death. So it means K chose to die.
Why did he choose to die? One reason is
that maybe he was 86 years old. He
didn't care anymore. Secondly, his death
unified the people of Iran.
You don't do such things. You don't
assassinate
a head of government.
Even those Iranians who may not have
supported the government previously may
now be outraged as by what the America
the who the Americans and Israelis did.
So Kame chose to sacrifice his life
essentially to to give Iran a better
chance. That's what it did.
Developer Kapay says how does this
conflict reach a con conclusion Iran?
Well, there's lots of different
scenarios in in which this this conflict
stops. One scenario is that nobody wins
and then there's a ceasefire.
One scenario is that the Americans and
and Israelis start running out of
defensive interceptor missiles.
Then they ask for a ceasefire which
would be humiliating which means they
don't ask for a ceasefire but do
something drastic like use nukes
perhaps. I don't know. That's that's
also a possibility. Another another
possibility is that is Iran is defeated
and there's a regime change. Another
possibility is that Iran refuses to be
defeated and it is bulcanized. There are
all kinds of possibilities right now.
It's just day three right of the
conflict. So I don't know how the
conflict ends right now. I am not
somebody who makes predictions.
No, I'm not that guy. I'm saying there
are multiple scenarios. The most likely
scenario
is the bulcanization of Iran.
Hopefully I'm wrong.
Sedar Suresh says, "Is a cornered Iran
likely to resort to terrorism for
revenge in the long run? Is Pakistan
weakened by aggravating SA relations
with other nations? Pakistan is not
weakened. Pakistan has American support.
Without with American support, you are
never weakened." Uh, is a cornered Iran
likely to resort to terrorism for
revenge in the long run? A cornered Iran
is likely to resort to guerrilla warfare
and proxy warfare in the long run if if
it is cornered if it is bulcanized or
whatever.
Yeah, they will 100% in that case resort
to guerrilla warfare and proxy warfare
which some people could call it call
terrorism.
Ojas Kumar says why do you think that
India is becoming a vasal? Even in 2008
the US pressurized India to not
retaliate to 2611. Do you think that
India can maintain military political
sovereignty in US orbit? If you are in
the US orbit, you have no genuine
sovereignty. Why do you think India
could be becoming a vasal? Well, there's
a whole number of things, right? It's
not one thing. It's a whole pattern that
points in a certain direction. I have
still not officially called India an
American. First of all, okay, just for
the just for the record, here is my
tweet from two hours ago.
Just for the record, my tweet from two
hours ago, there are six sovereign
nations on the planet and India is very
much one of these nations. Okay.
But yes, there are big concerns right
now. The Americans ask us to stop buying
Russian oil. We kind of stopped buying
Russian oil. Now we are restarting
apparently. I'm not sure if it's true,
but but we did almost stop buying
Russian oil for for a while. The past
few weeks. Yeah.
They asked us to move out of Chabahar.
We moved out of Chabahar,
right? Um pack silica if you see the
clauses and conditions it's kind of
vasalish.
Uh
then the AI thing,
the AI summit and um and Google setting
up um its $15 billion investment in
Vishaka or wherever it is. Uh they're
going to have Indian
Indian uh bureaucrats and officials
using
Google AI software.
There'll be scam detection built into
it. So the Indian government will run on
Google AI software Gemini possibly
software that is developed by Google
foreign company on Google on on foreign
hardware on foreign chips and controlled
by controlled from the United States. If
India's government runs on Google AI
software,
on Google artificial intelligence, they
will know exactly what's happening at
every level of the government, top to
bottom, in a granular manner. Do you
think that's a sovereign nation's
behavior
and the fact that our
officials, politicians, etc.,
They have family members who are foreign
citizens up top to not entirely top to
bottom but you get the point.
If you look at all these things put
together it's pointing in a certain
direction. Please open your eyes my dear
people.
Also I there's more the situation in
India's far east.
Take the example of Manipur. More than
half of Manipur is under under foreign
occupation.
The government of India doesn't control
what happens in more than half of
Manipur.
Do you call that sovereign behavior?
There's so many data points I can point
at. In case you people are not aware of
it, please open your eyes and become
aware.
Vive Singh says, "Is it a possibility
that Russia made a deal with the US in
exchange for Iran? Russia gets rid of
sanctions and can export oil to India.
Russia doesn't care about exporting oil
to India and for that they will not make
a deal with the US. Sanctions, Russia is
doing well under sanctions. Russia's
economy is growing. GDP is growing. Look
at the GDP growth of the of the European
nations, EU nations. Their GDP growth is
negative.
That's called recession.
But Russia's GDP growth is positive
despite a million sanctions dumped upon
them. When Russia is doing well, why
will it make a deal with the US? The
sanctions have strengthened Russia
actually,
right? So
the only
reason the Russians would make a deal
with the US if is if they get a very
favorable set of terms uh that end the
Ukraine war like big territorial gains a
regime change in Kiev, Netanyahu being
replaced by somebody else that that sort
of thing. In that case the Russians may
make a deal. Yeah. But they'll do it
very carefully. They'll not just
randomly make some deal. Oh now we can
export oil to Russia. We'll export it
anyway. What will you do? They'll say to
the to the Americans,
the Russians don't need America's
permission to export oil to some
country. Okay. So, no, not that case.
Um, here is my courses. We will face
either angry or shadow tariffs at the
coming future or new purchases of
Russian oil. Yep. Yep. If we are if we
resume purchase of Russian oil, if you
resume purchases of Russian oil, we will
face tariffs once again.
Kir Starmer's reply on the war was
pathetic. I have not really paid
attention to Kir Starmer because he is a
non- entity. Kir Starmer is a pathetic
little non- entity. I don't pay
attention to what he says. So I'm not
aware. Sorry, I'm not aware.
Okay.
Re
Samyaka
says, "Your take on Aravind X accounts
on strategic silence by India in this
war with regards to operation sindur
preparation similar decap at Pakistan. I
have no idea. I don't know. I don't
follow that account and uh I'm not aware
of what he or she has said. He has said
it's Arin. It's a male. I don't know
what he has been saying. I don't know.
Sorry.
Janel says, "A news came out just an
hour ago that India will be buying five
more S400 squadrons. Doesn't that mean
that we are still far away from being a
US vasal?" It is very positive and it
may induce me to not put India on the
non-asal on the Wasal's list. It's a
positive development. It's very good.
Very good. It's a positive news. If
India is buying four more 500 squadrons,
excellent. It means that we are still
some distance away from being a vasal.
US full-fledged US fac. But
technologically we are a vasal already.
Understand that? Okay.
Funesh Pande says a big fan since six
years. Thank you very much. So sir,
thank you so much indeed. But I have a
small disagreement. I hope it doesn't
make you angry. It's fine. Please
disagree. It's fine. Let me consider
your viewpoint so that I also understand
things better perhaps. Uh Modi said to
Israel,
Modi also said to Israel that about
early secession, I mean we are neutral
but if we are not, aren't we smart?
Like I keep saying my dear friends,
words don't matter.
Yeah, Mr. Modi has said to that there
should be early secession of war. That's
a diplomatic statement. That's a
diplomatic statement.
Um
yeah, there's some more. Okay, let's see
Mr. Modi's Twitter Twitter account
again. Uh I think he has put up some
more tweets in the past hour or two. uh
spoke with his his majesty king Abdullah
II King of Jordan conveyed our deep
concern of the evolving situation in the
region. We a re reaffirm our support for
peace, security and the well-being of
the people of Jordan. I thanked him for
taking care of the Indian community in
Jordan at this difficult hour. Allah
okay I no longer can read Arabic. Lost
the touch. Um yeah that's that's the
last statement. See listen. Okay.
Where's the statement about Israel?
Let's see. Let's see. Let's see. Let's
see. Okay. Yeah. conveyed India's
concerns about recent developments,
emphasized this that that India
reiterates the need for an early
secession of hostilities. That is
essentially an empty statement. That is
a statement everybody makes. That
doesn't make us neutral.
That is a very nice facade to perhaps
look neutral.
Okay. Words. Please stop taking words so
seriously. My dear friends, please. How
many times do I have to beg you all
stop taking words so seriously
right please don't we are in neutral we
are on the side of the US and Israel and
I'm not angry with you I'm not angry
with you it's fine you can disagree
maybe I'm not able to explain properly
enough maybe that maybe that's my fault
okay so I'm not angry
mama buff Bucket Mama bucket VFX says
Trump Putin she versus deep state asset
EU Iran UK Venezuela. But what is the
question? Trump Putin and she are on one
side and deep state asset EU, Iran, UK,
Venezuela are on another side. Uh I'm
not sure what you're getting yet. I'm
not I'm not able to get it.
How are the EU, Iran, UK, and Venezuela
in the same basket, in the same boat?
They're they
they're not.
Keshov says, "What is the long-term
consequences of this war to Armenia?"
See, if Iran is defeated, yeah, good
question. If Iran is defeated or
balkcanized, Armenia essentially has a
slim chance of survival, very small
chance of survival. The Turks and the
Aarbanis will eat them.
So it is very important for Armenia that
for Armenia's survival that Iran
survives.
Yeah, that's the long-term consequences
for Armenia.
Omnak says, "Where did Kami actually
die? Did he really refuse to move to a
safer place and why Iran was not able to
develop nuclear weapons? Were they
fearful?" Yes, Kabi refused to move to a
safe location. He chose to remain in his
residence knowing exactly what would
happen. So he chose to die. Yeah.
What do what do they say? Martyr. He
chose to die. That's the only
that's the only explanation I have for
him being assassinated in his own
residence. Now why was Iran not able to
develop nuclear weapons? Were they
fearful? Probably they were scared. I
think Khabi was against the nuclear
weapons for some reason. Um were they
scared that they will have more
sanctions or something? I'm not sure
what it was. They have been enriching
uranium hexafluoride for
decades at least a decade and a half.
When did stuckset happen? Stuckset was
at least at least 15 years ago, wasn't
it? The stuckset uh worm
stuckset
2010. That's 16 years ago. Right.
Right. And you can look it up. I'll not
explain what it is right now. You can
look it up later. Struct is a very
interesting thing. So Iran has been
uh enriching uranium hexaf hexafluoride
for at least two decades I would say.
So after two decades they would
certainly have enough facile material
for a handful of warheads
highly enriched uranium right they would
have it. So why didn't they do it? I
have no idea. Doesn't make any sense.
Maybe Mr. the Kame was against nuclear
weapons for because of some principle or
maybe Iran was too scared to officially
become a nuclear weapon power. I'm not
sure but yeah it's it's well
things would have been different if they
had officially tested a new two
right angle says if I become prime
minister which minister should I give to
you
I don't know
maybe gave me the prime ministership in
that case
okay mittin says I think Iran can't be
won without boots on the ground. Like I
said so many times, you can't do a
proper regime, an actual regime change
without boots on the ground. So the next
best thing is break up Iran, fragment
it.
That's a viable possibility.
Yeah. So yeah, you can't do a regime
change without boots on the ground, but
you can fragment the nation by by by
devastating the nation and by depleting
the nation's firepower and resources and
causing chaos all across the place so
that there is no unified command by
decap decapitating the command and
control structure. All of those things
we do then Iran can possibly become
fragmented can be bulcanized and that's
a good opt good good good outcome for
the US and in Israel most likely
right angle says did you check my mail
few months back I sent you swastik in
your thoughts if you have not received I
will resend it again thank you for
everything I haven't seen your email I
get and I'm sorry for that I I know many
people send me emails but I am not able
to read all the emails because I get so
many of those. Um
and uh yeah I I if I if I read all the
emails I'll be able to do nothing else
right because there are so many emails.
So I really really am sorry to those of
you I'm sure there are others also who
have sent me emails and I've not
responded or not read perhaps
uh I'm sorry for that. Okay. But it's
it's physically it's it's not humanly
feasible for me to read all the emails
and study them and respond to them. It's
not possible.
Uh so I've not seen it. So if you want
to know about the swastik
tweeted about the swastik in the past.
Okay. So
uh let's let's go here.
I have a whole what Twitter thread very
longlasting Twitter thread.
uh
about the swastik
lots and lots and lots and lots of
tweets from 2016 by the way
uh about the swastika you can look it up
so I have yeah I' I've done that but in
case you have something to that you
would like to me to look into uh
do send an email again I'll I'll try and
see it, sir. All right. And apologies
for not reading it thus far.
Okay.
MRA says Pakistan, Afghanistan, Iran,
US, Israel target civilian aircraft.
Civilian aircraft.
Um the US does target civilian aircrafts
when they feel like. If you don't
believe me, I can show you historical
evidence.
It's it's just a fact. Okay.
Okay, check this out. USS Vincson's
shoots down Iranian civilian plane July
3, 1988.
Okay, Iran Airflight 655. Let's take a
look at this. This is a shoot down in
1988.
It was an international scheduled
passenger flight from Thran to Dubai.
There was shot down on 3 July 1988 by
two surfaceto-air missiles fired by an
American warship.
All 290 people on board were killed.
It happened during the Iran Iraq war.
Um
so there was no apology from the US and
they paid some money 61.8 8 million as
an excgraia payment to the families of
the miss victims and the US did not
admit liability for the shoot down.
Okay, so that's a historical event. The
Americans shot down a civilian airliner
and uh did not apologize don't did not
admit liability but paid some money.
So the US did I'm not sure if there are
other instances but they did target a
civilian aircraft. Afghanistan I don't
know if they have ever targeted civilian
aircraft. Iran I don't know Israel I
don't know Pakistan
Pakistan once shot down an aircraft in
which a chief minister was flying an
Indian chief I think chief minister of
Gujarat or something. So that's that's
kind of a civilian aircraft isn't it?
It's not a military aircraft. So they
did that the Pakistanis.
So you have these things. Yeah. Hardik
Jooshi says I feel India has become
diplomatic by siding with Russia when it
comes to oil and siding with the US when
it comes to Israel Iran. Doesn't that
constitute best interests like I have
said India is taking practical
decisions. India is multi-aligned. India
is doing whatever it can. India is
always following its national interest
based on the current situations, the
current circumstances and India's
capabilities which are very low right
now. It is what it is. I at the
beginning of this live stream I said
that India has picked a side. India has
chosen a side which is US and Israel and
their allies. And India has chosen this
side for practical reasons not
ideological reasons.
So he's called being practical and
pragmatic
right not being idealistic.
So yeah it does constitute our best
interest though
depending on the options that we have as
of now it does.
Ritik says will you consider Kami a
great leader? I am
will I consider Kam a great leader? Um
um great leaders
I consider Putin to be a great lead
leader.
Xiinping I'm not sure historically Phil
God was a great leader but there are
very few people I consider to be great
like historically long long duration
long horizon great leaders. I don't
think uh Mr. Kame will fall into that
category.
And when it comes to Mr. Putin, time
will tell actually if he if he's truly a
great leader or not. It's too early to
say even now.
The Mandian, thank you very much for
becoming a YouTube member, sir. Thank
you so much.
Uh Cosmic Cab says Indian government
bowed to us too soon. Can we blame the
Indian government? No, India has not
bowed to the US too soon. India has not
bowed to the US too soon.
India
resisted as long as it could.
Operation Sindur was a resistance.
In the aftermath of Operation Zindur,
when Trump kept claiming that he stopped
the war, we resisted.
We resisted signing a lopsided trade
deal with the US. That was also
resistance.
We bowed down in the in the last few
weeks only
slowly and even now I'm not 100% sure if
we should be called a vasal state. We
may be I will revisit and reanalyze that
after this Iran war is over. Okay
Sid Seagel says what situation do you
see India getting getting involved?
What getting involved in what?
In the war. India is not getting
involved in the war no matter what
happens. Uh are you referring to any
other situation? I'm not sure what the
question is. It's not sufficiently
clear.
It's not India is not getting involved
in the war
no matter what happens. Iran Iran war no
we are staying out of it. Other
situations well we are part of the
world. We are involved in a million
other situations.
Okay. Shabish says Pakistan, Venezuela
and now Iran. Chinese air defense seems
to be failing big time. Typical of them
to supply supply inferior stuff or
outdated design itself. Nonetheless, our
electronic warfare capability in jamming
tech was topnotch too. So in operation
Synindur, we've discovered that we have
one of the world's best air defense
systems, multi-layered air defense
system, right? We it was outstanding,
brilliant electronic warfare capability
also. I I hear that India has excellent
EW capabilities. Yeah. When it comes to
Chinese air defense equipment, radars
etc. It performed miserably in operation
Synindur. Venezuela.
In Venezuela, Maduro was given up.
The Americans had to use almost no force
at all in Venezuela. It was a backdoor
backroom deal.
Okay. So the so Chinese air defense was
not tested in Venezuela. Iran, it's
possible that Chinese air defense is
failing right now. Possible, but it's
not like Iran only uses Chinese air
defense. So yeah, so overall it's clear
that the export versions of Chinese
systems aren't great. That much we can
say for sure.
Kul Singh says, "Will India ever be
superpower?"
Will India ever be a superpower after
siding with the US in this war and
losing its sovereignty?
See maybe you are new to this channel.
On this channel we don't use the word
superpower in in vishuru. Indians are
obsessed with superpower being
superpower and being vishwaguru.
So we not discussing vishuuru here. So
I'll not discuss that. But superpower
you have to first be a regional power to
be a superpower.
Huh? You have to first be a regional
power.
Is India a regional power in the Indian
subcontinent? The Americans did a regime
change in Pakistan in 2022 by removing
Imran Khan and bringing Shabb Sharif in
India's backyard. Could India do
anything? No. No. No. In 2024, the
Americans did a regime change in
Bangladesh. They ousted pro- India Shik
Hasina and brought in Muhammad. Could
India do anything? No. No. No. Then the
Americans did a regime change in Nepal.
Could India do anything? No. No. No. We
are not even a regional power
in the Indian subcontinent. The US is
more powerful than India. So what
superpower? First learn to be a regional
power. Right?
Vive Singh says seeing the cry in many
parts of bat. Clearly the minority is an
illusion. Global majority is the reality
and indic faith are victims. Question
why can't we have bumutra law like
Malaysia?
99% of Indians are not even aware of
what the Bumhiputra law of Malaysia is
which
gives
higher status to indigenous people.
Bumiputra right
and their culture
in India the Bumiutras are
are secondass citizens. Why can't we
have it? Because India is a secular
nation. It is a secular constitution. It
has secular laws and the government
loves secularism and worships the
constitution. That's why we can't have
these things. We can't have nice things
in India because our standards
are poor and the entire fabric of the
nation of the governance system, the
constitution, the laws, the
institutions, everything is hindophobic.
India is a hindu apathide state.
Vishal Ro says by neutrality I meant not
going to the US side and S400 news was
on ANI digital X page. All right sir.
All right. Got it. Thank you. Verdan
Vive says India China dumping US
treasury bonds and buying gold silver.
So market crash coming in the US.
US real estate crashing news is India is
buying S400. India go for P today as
Saudi official said US abandon users.
All these things are happening different
pieces of context clearly. Uh a Saudi
official I saw something on Twitter that
a Saudi Let's see uh we have Twitter
here. Yeah, we have Twitter. Let me
reboot Twitter and open a new fresh
page. One second. Yeah, let's put that
on the screen.
Okay. So, we have Twitter here and Mr.
Modi is writing about King Abdullah II
of Jordan, I suppose. Yeah. Okay. So, um
Saudi official, right? Okay. Let's
remove this
uh Saudi. So, the
uh
why would I use my voice? Saudi official
said US abandoned them.
Let's see. Do we have something?
Okay. So this Saudi official says
America has abandoned us. It's focusing
its defense systems on protecting. Yeah.
Like we did like I said a while ago.
Yeah. So a Saudi official is has said
that they they're upset obviously and I
don't blame them. Yeah. So yeah, these
are some developments that are happening
in real time as we speak right now.
Yeah. Har CR says why hasn't Mod why
Modi hasn't exed anything regarding
Kame's death? Because India has chosen a
side. India has chosen the side of
Israel and the US. That's why Mr. Modi
will not speak about Kab's death. He
will not offer any condolences to Iran.
Okay. India has chosen a side.
Hanish says, "Interestingly, the US is
destroying its own F4s, F-15s, F5s, and
F-14s. What happened to the kill switch?
Everyone's aware they have it. The US is
destroying its own F4s, F5s, and F-14s.
I I'm not aware of the context.
I'm not aware of the of the context.
The US is destroying its own F4s, F5s,
F-14s. Um, I'm sorry. I'm not aware.
Sorry.
All right. Next. Modi G weeks ago speech
about decolonization of India's Indian
minds by 2035 this by Deepak dating
coach nice name Modi G weeks ago speech
about decolonization of Indian minds by
2035 m topic was never discussed by
content creators their identity ego is
based on it looks like we are fighting a
lost battle
um
so Mr. Modi spoke about decolonization
of Indian minds by 2035 and something
about Macaulay
and content creators did not discuss
this topic.
Okay. So I'm sure there's a bunch of
Indian content creators who focus on Mr.
Modi and what he says and then they I
suppose analyze that and discuss that
and what you're saying is that nobody
discussed this particular uh speech of
Mr. Modis
um identity ego is based on it I'm not
based on what are we fighting a lost
battle
um
the battle of what decolonization the
decolonization will happen through
government policies right by by through
government reforms because the whole
system keeps Indians mentally colonized
and progressively further colonizes
Indians
and the system has to be changed and
only the government can do it. So, as of
now, it's not happening, but it's not a
lost battle.
It can still be done.
And and speeches about this or that are
fine, but we want actual actions, not
just speeches. So, that's why um Yeah.
Yeah. So,
I I I can't say about content creators
what they do. They have their own thing,
agenda, their own their own decisions
they make, right? I personally don't
analyze these things. I look at
geopolitics, history and science. So I'm
not a I was not aware of this. All
right.
The awesome film says where is your
course geopolitics from first principle
should be there I suppose.
Yeah should be there
wherever it was.
Arismanticor says hypothetically how
would a nuclear Iran change the
situation in West Asia? Is Pakistan
trying to create a corridor to Bram Cove
straight into Afghanistan? Well, if
Pakistan is trying to do that, it's very
far away from actually achieving that.
Right. So I I have not seen any actions
by Pakistan that indicate that they're
trying to create a corridor to Bram.
I've not seen any actions thus far. I
mean the war is going on Pakistan
Afghanistan but Pakistan isn't going
into Afghan territory and grabbing
territory and trying to create a
corridor. So, so that's not happening.
How would a nuclear Iran change the
situation in West Asia? It would balance
out Israel,
right? Mutually assured destruction.
I've got nukes, you've got nukes. Don't
cross certain lines. Otherwise, mutually
assured destruction. So, that completely
changes the balance of power
and the and the options that various
nations have. If you have a
nuclearpowered nation in that region,
totally changes everything.
Pratip Kumar Roy says, "I read somewhere
three American F-15s have been shot down
and Netanyahu's office was hit by an
Iranian missile. Is he alive?" Okay,
let's So, I also heard three F-15s were
shot down in Kuwait.
So, let's see uh if we have any further
updates
uh on on on
Twitter. Let's see. Netanyahu
Netanyahu
Yahoo.
Let's see. Is there anything going on?
Is there any update?
I don't know what this is.
Okay,
let's see if there we have something
latest.
Okay, some people are making all kinds
of uh claims. I don't know about that.
If you go to the latest stuff, you'll
see all kinds of crazy crazy tweets.
Um,
yeah, I'm not sure if I am seeing
anything about anything happening to
Netanyahu. Some people are claiming
Netanyahu is dead. Obviously, some
people will do that. Everybody has an
agenda
and the prime minister of Israel account
has tweeted 26 minutes ago and it's Mr.
Nathano saying something. So officially
I don't see any indication that anything
has happened to Mr. Netanyahu. Okay. Uh
American F-15's going down. Let's see.
Kuwait.
Kuwait. Let's see.
Um this is the latest. Oh god.
Yeah, Twitter is a dangerous place
actually. All because of random stuff
pops up.
Okay. cats aircraft.
Yeah. So, looks like a bunch of u
American aircraft were shot down in
Kuwait and we'll analyze later how it
happened.
Honey Sharma says, "Sar is Iran and
Israel war is so interesting. They both
look right in their position from our
perspective. Iran is fighting for its
existence and so is Israel. At the end,
is it just survival of the fittest?
Geopolitics is about survival of the
fittest.
Geopolitics is also about the rule of
the jungle. The rule of the rule of the
jungle. Uh so Iran is fighting for its
existence. Israel is not fighting for
his existence. Israel is fighting to end
Iran. The war was not started by Iranian
actions. Remember that the war began
with Israeli strikes on Iran and then
the subsequent assassination
of Mr.
So, Israel is fighting
for a regime change in in Iran and Iran
is fighting for its survival.
Some people may disagree with what I am
saying, but this is how I see it. It is
definitely surv survival of the fittest
and it's also the law of the jungle.
Yeah, that's geopolitics.
The Sumit Maya says, can Iran survive
the next what week? What's the end goal?
So whether Iran can survive one the next
one week depends
on how many more missiles does Iran have
and can they rem can the missile
launchers remain hidden from American
and Israeli surveillance
because Iran doesn't have a great air
force. Iran has highly sophisticated and
capable missiles. So number one, how
many more missiles does Iran have? If
they have 10 20,000 more missiles and
maybe 10 20,000 more drones, they could
definitely last more than a week. But if
their stocks are getting depleted, then
they may not last a week. And even if
they have lots of missiles, but the
Americans then find out where the
missiles are stored,
then they could take out the storage
sites, then Iran may not be able to last
long. So it depends on a variety of
factors. The end goal of Iran is to
survive. The end goal of America and
Israel is to do a regime change in
Israel. If that doesn't work, they will
want to bulcanize and break up Israel.
Sorry, Iran. Iran.
Aristot has become a new member. Thank
you very much, sir. Thank you very much.
Welcome to the channel's membership.
Thank you. And YouTube is messing up his
membership again. Was member before
YouTube. Maybe it's not a big fan of me
perhaps. I don't know. So, sorry that
this happened to you. And welcome back.
Thank you.
Uh Dvadasra says is China
messed up? Has the US surrounded them
properly? See, China is fine.
China doesn't have any military issues
right now. The US has definitely
surrounded them thoroughly, encircled
them.
See, if you look at the geography,
where is map? Here is map. We put map on
the screen. Yes.
So here's the map. If you look at China,
the whole of Japan is a gigantic
American fortress. More than 130
American military bases. South Korea,
more than 100 military bases of America.
Taiwan, an American fortress once again.
Then you have Guam. Where is Guam? Where
is Guam? Here is Guam. Major American uh
military, naval and air force base. So
there there is this there are these
three island chains that completely hem
in China. China is surrounded from that
that that perspective. China has been
bullying Vietnam and the Philippines. So
they're also pro- US. Okay. Myanmar
there's a war going on civil war which
nobody hears about these days. So at
least from this perspective, China is
encircled from the east and the south.
China has deliberately maintained very
bad relations with India which means
India is not friendly with China. So
that's also an issue with for China. And
in the in the north you have Russia
which does not trust China. Currently
they are cooperating because of because
of the situation. So China is obviously
encircled in a certain sense not
completely encircled but surrounded from
multiple directions because of their own
bad policies.
Uh economically they are very powerful
technologically they are great. They
have one of the world's best education
systems. militarily they are untested
and the US is just way too powerful for
the for the Chinese and that nuclear
deterrent isn't that great. So that's
the situation for China. Pratep Kumar
Roy says will Pakistan get involved now
since Saudi has been hit by an Iranian
missile. Can India get involved in this
war in the future? India should not
under any circumstances get involved in
this war and I hope it doesn't and I
don't see it happening. Uh will Pakistan
get involved because Saudi Arabia has
been hit by Iranian missiles?
Well, they have this mutual defense
agreement, right? Saudi Arabia and
Pakistan. So if the Saudis invoke that,
then Pakistan will be duty bound or
treaty bound to come to the aid of Saudi
Arabia in a military way.
So then the the Pakistanis will have to
decide shall we honor the agreement we
have or shall we betray the Saudis.
I think it's still kind of uh at this
point less likely that Pakistan gets
involved directly at this point but in
the future in the coming days that it
may perhaps get involved. We'll see.
Vincious Venicious
fan says Israel is losing support in the
US and the next generation of US leaders
might be anti-Israel. Considering many
of them are seeing through the Israeli
possession of the US in that case would
India be the next host
um
I think there may be many uh American
politicians who are not pro-Israel but
overall Israel still has a lot of
support in the US
bipartisan support
uh the next generation of US leaders
might be I don't know maybe may not be I
I don't know I don't
Um,
in that case, could India be the next
host? Host
host.
I don't know. I don't know.
Honey Sharma says, "Kim Jong F feels
like the kid who has all the expensive
toys, but nobody's willing to play with
him. But he's got some of the coolest
toys, doesn't he? So that that makes up
for everything else. I suppose
says F-35 would be a stamp of salad. I
agree. I agree. That will be the like
the stamp official recognition
certification.
I agree with you. I agree with you.
So let's watch out for that. If that
happens, it's an official certificate of
vasalhood.
Pratip Kumar Roy says, "Taliban hit
Durkhal air base by drone attack."
Outstanding job Taliban. Outstanding job
Afghanistan.
We give full support to Afghanistan.
Absolutely. Good job.
Adil B says, "If Iran had gotten a hold
over the nukes, will that be disastrous
for the world?" Because that's the
narrative the West is Yeah. Uh pushing.
Iraq weapons of mass destruction
similarity here. See if hypothetically
Iran has nuclear weapons, will it be
disastrous for the world?
It won't be disastrous for the world.
Iran is not a bunch of crazy people,
right? Iran is a very responsible
nation. They have behaved very
responsibly since 1979.
The Americans claim they are the they
are a terrorist nation or whatever.
That's just claims. We know they're not
terrorist nations. They're not. We know
here in India that Iranians aren't
terrorists. It's the Pakistanis
who the Americans love who are
terrorists, not Iran.
And Iran has been a pretty responsible
nation. The way I see it, if they had
nuclear weapons, it would have perhaps
made West Asia more stable.
Probably it would have made West Asia
more stable than what it is right now.
And that would be actually better for
the world. You know true multipolarity
is like 15 20 nations with nuclear
weapons. That is true multipolarity.
So I don't agree with the western
narrative. I don't
nobody's Buddha says longtime follower
from DXB.
DXB Dubai. Let me just check what DXB
mean. But thank you so much for being a
longtime follower. What is DXB? I think
it's Dubai. DXB Dubai.
Okay. DXB Dubai. Yeah. Right. So, thank
you so much, sir. Thank you so much for
being a longtime follower. Really
appreciate that. Um, Dubai is partially
resuming flights soon. Your thoughts?
Sort source DXB media office.
Okay. Partially resuming flights soon.
Well, that that's good news then. It's
good news for the people who need to
travel in and out and uh
yeah I mean what are my thoughts? My
thoughts are that it's it's positive
news. It's good news and uh I'm sure
this decision will be taken in a very
responsible manner in the sense that if
there is any threat to any to any
civilian aircraft then the resumption
should not happen. So if there is the
partial resumption of flights, it means
that there is a high confidence that
civilian aircraft don't face threats at
least in some sectors. So overall I
think it's very positive news.
Venicious fan says everyone knows about
the roch shield and Jewish control
wasn't being hidden the purpose or are
they letting people know about
themselves on purpose about the
rochills? I haven't studied the raw
shields and people said that the Jews
control the world. I don't know about
that. I don't know about that. I haven't
studied history from this perspective
and I haven't studied this particular
set of aspects of history. So I
personally don't know much about the
Rostians. I hear a lot of people saying
this.
Are there any books about this? I I have
to look into this. I don't know. I don't
know.
So I am not the guy to right guy to ask
about Russians.
Her
hijab Bhya says if India buys F Sukoy 30
57 or the F35 is it still was if India
buys the Sukoy 57 India is definitely
not a vasal.
India still is a technological vasal
but buying Suko 57 is a big statement.
it will tremendously displease the
United States.
So if India does that, it's it's not a
vasal from the other perspectives.
Technologically we are assal
technologically we are completely
dependent on the US.
Okay. Nahush Achara says Nahusha Achara
says do you think the presence of 6
million Indians in Gulf countries made
India pivot this time? Is it it's
difficult to evacuate them unlike
students from Ukraine?
The reason for India's pivot is not the
6 million Indians.
The reason for India's pivot is
American pressure.
Okay, that's the reason for India's
India's pivot.
And it's not like those 6 million people
are being targeted by anybody.
They're actually a big asset for India
in the Gulf region. So it's not the
presence of those 6 million or whatever
Indians that has made made India choose
a certain side. It is pure and simple
pressure applied by the US.
Frantic Gamer says so India is vasal.
Really by that logic China was a vasal
of the US well as well in the 80s and
90s. Their entire manufacturing
infrastructure was dominated by US
companies.
I'm talking about today.
And once again, for the record,
for the record.
Uh where are we? For the record, my dear
friends,
as of today, this is my stand. There are
six sovereign nations. India is one of
them as of today.
Right? And I will reinvestigate and
reanalyze this after this war is over.
See, understand sovereignty.
Sovereignty is not some mythical
vague concept. Sovereignty can be
calculated and you can put a numerical
score on sovereignty.
What are the elements of sovereignty?
There is territorial sovereignty, there
is economic sovereignty, there is
legislative and policy based
sovereignty, there is um
technological sovereignty.
So if your territory is under your
control, you you have full territorial
sovereignty.
If you have your own currency and you
control your economy, then you have
economic sovereignty. There is military
sovereignty. If you completely control
your armed forces, you have military
sovereignty.
Then it
um legislative and policy sovereignty.
If you control your laws, you decide
your laws and you decide your policies
without external external interference.
Then you have
legislative and policy sovereignty. In
technology,
if you are completely independent from a
technological perspective, you have
technological sovereignty. All those
things you have to consider together in
an intelligent and analytical manner
with the right data and then you can
decide or determine whether a nation is
a sovereign nation or a vasal. Okay? So
it's not done based on emotions.
It's based on cold hard facts and clear
analysis. That is how we determine
whether a nation is sovereign or not.
I'm not putting out ideas into I'm not
pulling ideas out of air. I'm not saying
a nation is sovereign or vasal based on
my emotions whether I like the nation or
I hate it. That's not how it works.
All right.
Eno says is it true?
I don't know what is the meaning of
I don't know I don't know what do you
mean by
first of all bha you know the word bha
what it means it means slave
why do Indians use the word bha north
Indians
because that word was used by the Turks
to refer to Indians
mean these are all our slaves and then
it became part of everyday
Bha is a very very bad word. It means
slave and we use it for ourselves today.
That is the effect of long-term foreign
occupation.
All right.
says, "Can we say that World War II
started on 2023 in 2022 went on second
gear after attack on Israel 7th October
23, third gear by Operation Sundur, and
now it went on fourth gear in 2026?" No,
I don't consider the world to be in any
phase of World War II.
World War II means direct confrontation
between superpowers.
So in terms of nuclear weapons, Russia
is a superpower. It has more nuclear
weapons than the US. So a direct
confrontation, direct military
confrontation between Russia and the US.
That is third world war. Right now we
are in the cold war. It's a cold war
period but with more hor it's heating up
now. But it's not third world war.
Absolutely not.
Ah Bishra says, "Why is everyone
spamming beam beam in the chat?"
Well,
I wonder I wonder but I will allow it.
Infinenix says America is Armenia is 98%
Christian. Aharbaijan is 99% Shia
Muslim. Iran is 95% Shia. I'm confused
as to why Iran supports Armenia.
Azarbaijan is a Turic nation. Iran like
us is an Arian nation. Armenia has Arian
roots.
Azarbaijan is a vasal or you say you
could say an ally of Turkey.
Turkey and Armenia and Azarbaijan are
both Turk nations. They want to erase
Armenia from the map of the world to
create a panuran corridor corridor of
Turk nations. Armenia is the only
problem in the way. They want to erase
it.
If Turkey becomes more powerful, it's a
problem for Iran. That's why Iran wants
Armenia to not get destroyed and not not
get erased from the map of the world.
And India and Armenia
also and Iran also all all three of them
don't want Turkey to get more powerful
and more influential. That's why India,
Iran and Iran are working together to
help Armenia survive.
That's why a Hindu nation and a Shia
Islamic nation are working together
to save a Christian nation.
Gear TV says, "Do you think Iran will
use dirty bombs?" It depends on the
circumstances.
If Iran is in desperate straits,
then they'll use it.
Yeah.
Frantic Gable says also US will
devastate China defending China's orders
of magnitude stronger than attacking US
irrespective of how many bases it has.
Come on. Thank you for your input sir.
Thank you.
Pratip Kumar Royce says about Medici
bank and family world's oldest bank. I
have not studied this. Sorry.
Says for the next 150 200 years what's
the safest country to practice Hinduism?
Singapore, China?
Definitely not India.
Uh whichever country is stable and
neutral, religiously neutral.
Uh if China survives 200 years, then I
don't think China has anything
whatsoever against Hinduism.
If you live in China and you're
practicing Hinduism, the Chinese
government will do nothing to you.
Nothing whatsoever. China has no issue
with Hinduism.
Uh Singapore, sure is Singapore.
very nice place survives 200 years the
way it is Hinduism you can practice
there happily peacefully without any
issues
the US I'm not sure western Europe I'm
not sure Russia
as long as you don't do political
Hinduism which nobody does Russia has no
issues with Hinduism either
but definitely not India
India is a hinduhobic country right
angle says if you see if you see the
swastik properly it Beach mantra of Lord
Gpati gum drawn from four sides fancy
style in fancy style tell by my guru
Harishankar gji all right sir I'll look
into it okay
Gautam Gautam says can combined fire
power power of bricks challenge the US
no
I says are waiting for your how to raise
your standard series all right thank you
for the reminder sir thank Imagus
says, "Will there be a third world war?
What's your opinion?"
What's my opinion? I first of all hope
it never happens. Secondly, I think we
are still far away from a situation
where a World War II could happen. Still
far. I mean, not very far away, but we
are reasonably certain it will not
happen anytime soon, hopefully.
So, I hope it doesn't happen. And right
now it's not under any
it's not like it it could happen
anytime. Yeah.
Bipla says do you think India and China
are the reason behind this war in the
interest of the US? Not India. China is
see the US wants to what is the actual
objective of the US is to take control
of the entire world's oil resources.
Okay. Iran is a major oil exporter. 15
20% of China's imports come from Iran.
If the US can secure that, grab that,
then they can anytime cut down that 20%
that China gets from from Iran. The US
has already taken Venezuela
from which about 3% of China's oil was
coming. If it can stop Iran's oil to
China by taking control of Iran or by
fragmenting bulkizing Iran and then
taking it over piece by piece, then it's
a huge blow for China.
China's oil also comes from Saudi
Arabia, Iraq, UAE, uh Nigeria, other
countries. All of which the US can force
to stop selling oil to China.
So that is the objective to completely
control China's energy destiny and
China's energy resources from where
China gets energy. That's the objective.
India nothing.
Putin says, "Is John Mir Shimemer best
and most unbiased western analyst?" I
haven't really studied what he has to
say. I don't know. He seems to be pretty
famous these days, but I haven't I
haven't been listening to his lectures
and reading his stuff, so I don't know.
Hari Krishna says, "How vulnerable is
India's energy security if the straight
of hormones becomes militarilized,
militarized or partially closed?" Well,
currently today, as of right now, what
is the time? India's time. It's almost
11:00 p.m. India time on the 2nd of
March 2026. As of right now, the
straight of hormones is completely shut.
Completely shut.
What percentage of India's oil comes
from comes through the state of almost.
Let's find out. Must be more than 50%,
more than 60%.
Okay.
What percentage of India's oil imports
come through the strait of Hormuz?
35 to 50%. That is massive.
That's huge.
So right now the straight of Hormos is
shut down because there's a war
happening there.
If that lasts
a week, two weeks, if it lasts 3 days, 5
days, oil prices worldwide will go up
huge. they'll shoot up massively.
If that lasts a couple of month, a
couple of weeks or a month, the prices
of everyday items in India will become
way more expensive.
Okay? So, India will obviously reroute
its oil supplies, take buy way more from
Russia and so on, which could offset
what's happening here to a certain
extent, but it's going to make things
bad for India. So, India is very
vulnerable to a closure of the straight
of hormones, very much so.
Akar Ashkar says, "My wife and I are big
followers." Thank you very much to you,
sir, and to your wife. Thank you so
much. It's frustrating to see how much
to see how democracy is failing in
India. Do you think a military rule is
the ultimate solution?
Yeah, democracy isn't really working out
great for India. Democracy is the the
rule of the it's it's yeah it's
essentially
the standards are set to the lowest
common denominator in democracy. Right.
Democracy is all about ruling through
popularity then by ruling through high
standards. High standards are extremely
unpopular because they they require
sacrifices and pain. Short-term pain. No
one likes that. Everybody wants
short-term pleasure.
So that's why democracy brings your
standards down generation after
generation. So what's the solution?
Military rule I don't believe in
military rule. the right. We have to ask
ourselves
that today things are bad because of the
situation democracy all that when India
was great in the past what kind of
what kind of system of governance did we
have and the answer is straightforward
monarchy and imperial rule not military
rule monarchy
kings and emperors that's what always
worked for India Who was Chhatraati
Shwaji Maharaj? Who were what was the
Marata Empire? Was it democracy? Was it
military rule? No, it was imperial rule.
The Chola Empire, imperial rule, the
Gupta age, the Gupta era,
right? Samudra Gupta, Chundra Gupta,
Kumar Gupta, great emperors, the Kushan
era, the great Kadeshka, one of our
greatest emperors, the Morian Samaraja,
Chundra Gupta Moria and so on. Great
emperors. Who was Shiram? Was he a
military ruler? No, he was a king. Who
was Shri Krishna? Was he a military
ruler? No, he was a king. That's your
answer, sir. That's your answer.
Really? Now, Miss Patel says, "Am I
wrong to be skeptical of the HPV vaccine
for girls? I am skeptical of any
unnecessary additional vaccines."
>> So, I look,
I don't know. I I haven't I've heard all
kinds of I've heard all kinds of nasty
things about the G Bill Gates Foundation
and their HPV vaccine trials. Now, if
you ask if you try to research on a
surface level, it's they'll say it's all
been debunked, but I am suspicious and
I'm very skeptical.
Yeah, I am not necessarily saying it's a
bad vaccine. I don't know which vaccine
the government is insisting on using
right now.
But what is the HPV vaccine for? It's
for it's a human papilloma virus
vaccine. How do you get it? You get it
through unsafe
sexual intercourse and promiscuity and
all kinds of stuff. Why do girls need
that?
Why do 15year-old girls need that?
Are you saying that they will all be
promiscuous in the future in 3, four,
five years time?
I I I don't know really.
Vibhav Okay. Vibhav Kumar Dewangan.
Thank you very much sir. Thank you.
Re now says is it bad if we manufacture
a lot of foreign weapons?
If we manufacture them in India
through in using um indigenous resources
then it's fine.
If we acquire the technology to
manufacture foreign weapons here and we
manufacture them actually in in house
instead of assembling the components
that came from outside then it's good.
It's not bad.
Yes. Kaslibal says do you you think Iran
has the capability to close the straight
of hormones and it's and is it in their
self-interest to close it? Do you see
them closing it at some point? Well, the
last I checked it was closed. Let's
let's find out is it in their interest
sure absolutely
is the one second is the straight of
hormones closed right now
technically no
it's closed it's closed
technically I don't care about
technically in all practicality it is
closed it's closed it is in the interest
of the Iran of of Iran to close right
now. Absolutely. Absolutely.
And they have the capability. Absolutely
they have the cap capability. It's the
first time it's ever happened. So yeah,
Gear TV says, "Shouldn't India use this
important strategic moment to pursue its
objectives regarding Pakistan occupied
Kashmir and weakening Pakistan by
opening a front especially when Pakistan
is already at war with Afghanistan and
in its west in its north and US is also
occupied with the Iran conflict.
The US is occupied with the Iran
conflict, but the US has the cap
capability and the capacity to be to
keep an eye on everything else else
that's happening in the world.
That's number one.
Number two, Pakistan is definitely
occupied with the war situation it faces
with Afghanistan.
Yeah. But Pakistan also has sufficient
troops and assets deployed in the
eastern front with India. They will
never pull out those assets and put them
in front of Afghanistan. No, they will
not redeploy that. That is permanently
stationed facing India which is fine. We
can deal with that. The major problem
is that Pakistan is a US. Pakistan is a
invaluable US asset. The US for the past
several decades has used Pakistan as a
stick to beat India with.
Now we want P. We want regime change in
Pakistan. We want Pakistan to stop being
a terrorist nation. We can do that by
defeating Pakistan militarily and so on.
But the US will never allow this to
happen. The last time we went to war
with Pakistan in May 2025, the operation
Zindur 3-day war, the Americans forced
India to stop the war.
They arm twisted India into stopping the
war.
They will not allow India to start a war
again. And if India starts a war this
time with Pakistan, the Americans will
tariff the hell out of India and
sanction the hell out of India.
It's not like the Americans aren't
watching.
It's not like the Americans only have
two eyes that are focused in Iran right
now. The Americans have tens of
thousands of pairs of eyes. They have
departments focused solely on what they
call South Asia in India.
South Asia is an absolutely horrible
term. It's the Indian subcontinent. My
point is India can't dream of doing this
right now. I'll be very pleased if India
does it which will be a declaration of
independence actually and sovereignty.
But I think it's unlikely. It's
unlikely. It will be foolhardy for India
to do that unless we have US approval.
So I think it's unlikely.
So Rob Kulkarnney says why Russia and
China are not able to fight US through
Iran.
The Iran is fighting the US and Israel
on its own.
Right? And if Russia and China start
supplying Iran with weapons and all,
then the US will take it as a
declaration of war.
And Russia see China can't even supply
Iran. China is too far away. Have you
seen Have you seen the map?
Do I have to show the map for this?
Okay,
one second. I'll put the map on the
screen.
See,
look at the map.
See, this is Iran. Where is China? Far,
far, far away. How will China supply
Iran with whatever they want or they
need? Russia could supply Iran, but
Russia is already embroiled in a war
with in Ukraine. Russia could supply
Iran through the Caspian Sea. Russia
isn't that far away, right? So, Russia
could do it, but Russia is already
embroiled in a war in Ukraine
and it may not make a lot of sense for
them to get involved in a second major
war and China is too risk averse to get
involved in any military conflict.
So, China is unwilling. China may give
some some satellite intelligence and all
that
and Russia may may provide Iran with the
Glonas system G instead of GPS. The
Chinese may give Iran the BU system
instead of GPS. But that's the extent of
which to which they will help Iran as of
now. That's why Iran is fighting
entirely on its own. That's why I say
it's a completely sovereign nation. It
is demonstrating its sovereignty by
fighting for its survival alone.
Galler says and its sources mil blogger
etc agree our AMD
is invincible impregnable is tested
against all systems not just China
including now misinformation no pun
intended even Russia couldn't integrate
and intelligize to our level so we have
tremendous engineers and scientists in
India who are paid peanuts to do this
work and still
They have built up the best
battle tested air defense system in the
world. Anti-missile defense, anti- drone
defense, and so on. Anti-aircraft
defense. Incredible job. Brilliant job.
The no no amount of thanks is enough
to thank these
anonymous unknown engineers
who have done this for us. Yeah. So I
agree with you.
Hurry CR says means Modi is not allowed
to say even a formal condolence. China,
Russia, even Pakistan did that. How will
Iran take this if the regime survives
the war?
India has chosen a side. Mr. Modi will
not even say a for give a formal
condolence.
How will Iran take this? Iran will
remember this.
other nations will will will pay
attention to this development. Russia
will pay attention to this development.
Other nations that possibly were looking
at India as a as some kind of a world
leader will pay attention to this.
Yeah, this will have some kind of impact
on India's credibility and India's
standing as a sovereign nation. This is
not how a sovereign nation behaves.
These are facts. These are absolute
facts. Mr. Modi is not even allowed to
give formal condolences.
Yeah, clearly.
Vive Singh says, "Would you be acting
to attend the Conan Summit? It would be
a privilege to see you in person and get
Q&A on your RN invasion series page and
indicate.
Will I be attending the Conan summit?" I
am not aware of the Conan Summit.
Uh where is it held? When is it going to
be held? I haven't been contacted. If
you are the organizer, if you want me to
come, I'll be happy to come. I mean, I
I'll be happy to consider it given my if
my schedule allows it. Um if you want me
to attend and if if you're not the
organizer, you could ask the organizers
if you want. So, I'm not aware of this.
Sorry, I'm not aware.
Pratamesh Mishra says Modi's Israel
visit could be an evacuation mission
considering BB's Bodhi language. If it
was kissing the ring, I missed the
gloating.
Okay.
Uh evacuation mission.
Evac mission.
Uh if it was kissing the ring, I'll tell
you something. When somebody kisses a
ring, okay, hypothetically,
the person whose ring is being kissed
doesn't glute.
Yeah, that may happen in Bollywood
movies or Hollywood movies. Even in
Hollywood movies, where does the term
kissing the ring come from? It comes
from the godfather.
When the godfather's ring is kissed, do
you see m the godfather gloating?
That's not how the world works in the
real world. It may have worked like that
in in TV serals and movies not in the
real world.
M Patel says love from Spain Mr. Chawa.
Uh gracias. Gracias. Thank you. Thank
you so much.
Yeah.
Adil Ben says continuation to previous
question. Does backing militia
not being a bad actor like Iran backing
Houthis, Hezbollah, Hamas. They even
attacked Indian shipment previously.
um backing militia.
So the Houthis
are the government of certain parts of
Yemen,
right?
The West calls them a militia. They
consider themselves to be a legitimate
government.
When it comes to Hezbollah,
they are kind of running or ruling
Lebanon, aren't they?
Hamas.
Yes. So, it depends, you know, Iran is
doing whatever it can do to to survive
and to further its national interest.
Now for us I I mean some people call
these elements terrorist elements some
people call them militia some people
call them legitimate or semi-legitimate
governments depends on who you are and
how you see it. My point is the national
interest is always paramount
and you can decide what is a red line
that you want to cross and what is a red
line that what is not a red line for for
example for India terrorism is is a red
line. So India will never use any form
of terrorism whatsoever. That's that's
very clear. But some nations do it. I'm
not saying Iran is is is a terrorist
nation. Iran has allies
in West Asia. Syria was an ally. So the
Americans designated Syria as a
terrorist nation. Then the Houthis, they
are they are fighting for Yemen's
independence essentially. So that's why
they the Americans call them terrorists.
Hisbah well maybe they are terrorists or
whatever because they fight Israel right
that's why so what the west does very
well is whoever is against them put
titles on them or tags you terrorist you
terrorist and then then designate Iran
as a terrorist nation
so look that's how it is a game of
narratives it's a game of propaganda uh
Hamas they attacked Indian shipments
previously Hamas also supports Pakistan
in Kashmir Right. So there are so the
world is complicated overall. The world
is complicated. It is what it is. Hamas
obviously they they supported they have
cons consistently supported Pakistan's
claim on Kashmir. Yeah. Some Mamas
leader even visited Kok I believe in
support of Pakistan. So yeah, but but so
Hamas is definitely an enemy of India
and that's why I will never hear me
support Hamas in any way whatsoever.
Bloody bunch of terrorists. No question.
Uh but yeah, they have some utility for
for Iran.
Yeah. Okay. Uh next Ricky says, "Will
FIFA World Cup get cancelled this year?"
FIFA World Cup where is being where is
it being held held? I forgot. Uh I had a
question about this in the last live
stream also. FIFA World Cup. Uh let's
see. Let's Google it.
Where is the next FIFA World Cup being
held
in United States, Mexico and so on?
Canada, USA, Mexico. I don't see it
being cancelled.
It's far away from this situation. I
don't see it being cancelled.
Gallow says observations. One, Iran used
warning missile shots before actual
move. Second, hypersonics were moved.
Third, C in uh yeah, error probability
central circular error probability in
anti-land vectors is quite low, less
than 500
m at least.
Observations.
Okay. I'm not sure about Iran
using warning missile shots before the
actual move in this war. In the 12-day
war, it happened. Yeah, the the Iranians
actually gave warnings. In this war,
there I don't as far as I know there
have been no warnings because the
Iranians were attacked first and in a
very devastating way. I mean they killed
how many. So I don't know about this war
if this is happening warning shots but
last time it was there. Yes, hypersonics
are being used. We know that uh CEB
circular error probability in anti-land
vectors is quite low. Okay, I'm not
aware of that but okay.
House of discussion says America can
destroy any country in ours. So why are
its enemies more confident today than
ever before? Something is shifting and
it's not military.
Uh
I don't see its enemies being confident
right now. I mean one of the major
enemies let's say of America is China.
Do you see any confidence from China
right now?
China is super quiet right now.
Historically in the past 1015 years
their diplomats have been super brash
and super super aggressive. Where is
that today?
Do you call that confidence? It's the
exact opposite of confidence. China is
super quiet. Uncharacteristically,
unnaturally quiet.
Which other enemies does the US have?
Yeah, you could say Madur was an enemy.
See what happened to him.
I'm not sure what you are seeing, but
I'm not seeing that.
Aries Manticor says our tech stack will
will slowly be reclaimed. Not now, but
probably in 20 years. It will be
insidious and will seem like partial US
control shares transfer of technology. I
hope so. I hope so.
It can be done over 20 years. It can be
done. Yeah. So, let's hope so. Let's
hope it happens. Yes. Uh Giri says US is
poking Iran so that it will hit Middle
East harder so that the rich people and
investments come back to the US and
destroy Gulf autonomy. What's your take?
No, I I don't see it that way. The Gulf
region is is
it's an asset for the US.
I the US has no issue with the Gulf
being prosperous.
I I don't see it that way. The US is not
doing all this to to to to destroy G the
the autonomy of the Gulf countries. The
US is doing this to to destroy Iran and
to take control of the oil. That's the
reason. And it's doing this so that
China is further choked off. That is the
objective. That's how I see it. Harrier
says, "Do you think the US and the EU
are oligarchies?" The US is an
oligarchy. The EU is a it's a vasilized
region of the US. The US is is an
oligarchy. Yes.
Uh Putin says about Hinduism in Russia,
2% are Hindu in the Alaii region. Okay,
that's interesting. I wasn't aware of
the Ali region and Hindus there. Uh the
Buryats are are
Buddhists, Tibetan Buddhism, I believe.
But yeah, Ali region Hindus. Really?
Let's find out.
Hinduism in Russia's Al Thai region.
Uh small but notable population, 2% of
of the Alaii region. Do we have some
interesting images?
Okay. Okay. Interesting. Very
interesting uh fact that you brought up.
Thank you.
Smith Zi says, "Will the GCC countries
attack Iran in response to the attack on
their key cities?" No,
they don't have the strength. They don't
have the military power to do that. If
they dare to do that, they'll be they'll
face largecale missile attack from Iran.
They won't do it. They won't do it. Gora
TV says, "Seeing the Saudi Aramco
crumble down makes me concerned about
our critical assets like the Jamnaga
refinery. Are there any dedicated air
defense systems in place to protect such
key strategic installations?" So when it
comes to the Aramco refinery
uh which refinery was it that was hit
uh Rastanura refinery
and uh it's been temporarily shut down
after a drone attack. U the drones did
not directly hit the refinery that's
what one hears but there was some
indirect u debris that fell on the
refinery which set off a fire and so on.
what one hears what that's what the
official um news is. I'm not sure how
true or false it is but yeah. Okay. Uh
so yeah it it definitely will make you
concerned about massive critical
interests of our assets of ours like the
Jamagar refinery which is kind of on the
border right I mean if we look at okay
let's not look at it Jamagar western
India right
the question is do we have any dedicated
air defense system in place air defense
systems in place there well I don't know
I'm hoping we do and I am saying it
makes sense for us to have it.
I mean, why would we not have dedicated
air defense systems for such a crit
critical asset of ours? So, yeah, I'm
pretty sure we we have taken the
requisite measures.
Aris is manticores my India my India
tech my India tech stack prediction. The
government of India is probably prepping
backups for the eventuality when the US
uses its tech levers to vosilize us. it
will be a very painful and forceful
replacement.
Well, I will any any time take temporary
short-term pain for long-term u
for long-term um you know sovereignty
for long-term gains. It's like going to
the gym. Go to the gym if you're a
beginner. You go and lift weights and so
on. The first week, two weeks,
everything hurts.
Everything hurts. Even getting out of
bed hurts. Even sitting down hurts.
But if you push through a couple for the
first couple of weeks, it stops hurting.
I mean, this minor soreness, but nothing
like the first two weeks. And if you
continue for the next 3 months, 6
months, 1 year, you're going to see a
transformation. So that's so short-term
pain is going to be there. But it's
important that you push through that. So
I hope that you are right and I hope
that this happens.
HC 1746 is a new member. Thank you very
much sir or ma'am and welcome to the
channel's membership. Thank you.
Pawang says Pawang G says why can't
India take advantage and do operation in
Pakistan? Because the US won't allow us
because Pakistan is very important for
the US. The US openly blatantly supports
Pakistan. How many times has Aim Mun
visited the White House in the past few
months. They love Pakistan. Pakistan is
super useful for them. They will the
Americans will never allow India to
destroy one of their assets.
So
Vishnu Panchchal says how to solve
corruption in India by becoming
completely intolerant
of corruption. I mean we have laws
against corruption but what happens
the laws aren't enforced or if the law
is enforced then it the case gets bogged
down somewhere and so on you know that
sort of thing. So the thing the solution
is become completely intolerant of
corruption right and reform the
institutions that are possibly one of
the co you know causative of this in
some way or the other.
Netat Grep says does the non-use of
black magic in wars prove that it
doesn't exist?
I don't even know. I have no idea
whatsoever.
Um is the absence of evidence evidence
of absence? Not really.
But do I am I saying that I believe in
this? Absolutely not. So I have no idea
about this. Sorry. Arush Mahajan says
big fan. It is said thank you sir. It is
said 16 Chinese military play cargo
planes flew to Iran and soon after
takeoff they cut off transponders and
flew with supplies and jammers to Iran.
What are my thoughts? I I'm not aware of
this. I don't know.
Is it possible? It it may be possible
that this may have happened. Do you
think would it have happened after the
war began? I think that's unlikely
before the war began. It's possible the
Chinese sent some supplies. That's
possible, but I am not aware of it. So
yeah, it's it certainly is possible that
this may have happened.
Aries says, I mean official
vasilization, not just tech
vasilization. The whole critical market
is occupied by super giants. Yes. to be
against them would be electorally
inconvenient for any government to act
immediately.
Um,
okay.
The whole critical market is occupied by
super giants. You mean the mega
corporations and so on.
To be against them would be electorally
inconvenient for any government to act
immediately. Yeah. Yeah. All right.
Okay. Vive RC says how do you reckon one
can bring a systemic change for instance
monarchy or some other change etc if it
during chaos like wars or do you see
some progressive way to achieve it if so
how there is no progressive or or
non-destructive
way to achieve this
if you want to transform India into
let's say a presidential system right
now it's a parliamentary democracy right
with prime minister
if you want to transform the
How do you do it? Does the constitution
allow it? The constitution doesn't allow
that. I suppose let's say you want a new
constitution. How do you do that? Will
the constitution of India allow new
constitution to be brought in? Never.
If you want to make India a monarchy, a
non-democratic monarchy, does the Indian
constitution and Indian system allow
this? It doesn't allow it at all. There
is no legal way of doing it. So how do
you bring a systemic change in India?
Very very very hard to do it legally.
Impossible to do it legally.
So it can only happen during some state
of chaos where you to create a system
again from scratch or something.
Putin says possibility of September 11
like thing by Shia revenge. I I would
not even want to comment about that. I
hope it doesn't happen.
Ojas Smith Kumar says India India
sending three ships to tackle Houthis in
the Red Sea. Really?
Uh let's see.
Indian Navy Red Sea
deploy
early 2024. That's old news. Um,
Houthies.
Let's see. Navy Houthies. H. Okay. So,
I'm not seeing any news right now. I'll
have to dig if it is true. But yeah, I
don't know.
Godliness says, "Today, many of the
so-called right-wing geopolitics experts
are busy in lying and bootlicking for
the current establishment. But then we
have a kohhinuru who always stands for
with the truth. Thank you. Thank you
sir. Thank you. I don't know what the
other experts are doing. Uh as you all
may know I don't really uh watch
uh other podcasts or this the shows of
other experts. So I don't know what
they're doing. I do my thing and I try
to be as honest as I possibly can.
Sometimes I do self-censorship
because certain things you can't speak
but I never lie. Okay. So that much I
can tell you. Uh sometimes I may be
wrong wrong about something. Some people
may disagree with that but at least I'm
doing it honest honestly. So that's what
I can tell you and I'm very glad I'm
very very very
um grateful to have the support of all
of you. So thank you so much.
Uh Rrook play says why does Modi speak
about making India a superpower
internally but when it comes to
answering foreign powers he just cows
down see there's a difference between
capabilities and dreams there's a
difference between words and actions
so see Mr. Modi is the prime minister of
India. His job is to keep up the morale
of the country to keep people optimistic
and positive and he's so you can do
that. You should do that as a prime
minister and he's Mr. Modi is also a
politician. If he doesn't get votes, he
will not remain prime minister.
And he is the best prime minister we've
had in years, decades.
So because we are a democracy you also
have to get votes
and if you say superpower superpower
vishuru vishuru get votes why not
so so that's the difference between
words and actions now when it comes to
answering foreign powers we don't answer
foreign powers except maybe the US in
the case of the US it's just too
powerful and that's why we have to
sometimes
um give the Americans what they want but
not other countries right so please
understand it's not as black and white
as we see things to be. Mr. Modi is
doing the best he can, I'm sure. So
yeah,
Krishna BK says, "Explain why Muslims in
India are protesting the death of Ayat
and Muslims in Iran are celebrating."
Uh, I cannot speak on behalf of people I
don't know. So I don't know. I can't
explain how why are you asking me to
explain this? I don't represent either
groups that you're talking about.
I I can't explain. I don't have an
explanation. Sorry.
Jaw bro says, I have seen many videos of
Kim Jong-un inspect farms and projects.
Is it just PR or is he knowledgeable and
truly concerned about quality? See,
North Korea is a truly opaque nation.
And I don't know what uh Kim Jong-un's
competencies are, what his uh skills and
uh depth of knowledge are like. I don't
know.
I'm pretty sure he's concerned about
quality as the ruler of North Korea. I'm
pretty sure he's concerned about
quality,
right? I I am certain that Kim Jong-un
is genuinely concerned about the quality
of whatever is happening in his nation,
whether it's farms, projects, whatever.
So, I'm I'm sure about that.
Is he knowledgeable or not? I don't
know. And at the end of the day, it
doesn't matter as long as you're
concerned about quality and and and
improving standards. Even if you are not
knowledgeable knowledgeable, let's say I
have no understanding of farming, but
I'm concerned about the quality of
farming in the country, then whether I
have knowledge or not, as long as I am
being concerned and I'm taking the right
appropriate actions to incl to to ensure
that farming is done at high standards
in the country, it's fine.
So you don't have to be knowledgeable
about everything.
You understand? That's that's the
important point.
Kiki Susan says, "Thank you for your
time." So thank you very much indeed,
Susan G. Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Putin says, "I am said larly bahin like
seems schemes could end due to
oil price rises." Oh, I hope so.
Okay, that'll be one good outcome of
that. Then
King Ritik the Great says the whole
world is burning. So many things are
happening. Meanwhile, we Indians are
debating Abhishek versus Sanju and to
win the World Cup.
Well, the whole world isn't burning
right now. There's u trouble in West
Asia. There's a war there. There's
obviously a war between Pakistan and
Afghanistan also. But the whole world
isn't burning.
Um and look
I know many Indians are debating cricket
and all that but even even entertainment
is an important component of your life
right you can't work all the time I am
not against entertainment
so if watching cricket for a couple of
hours in a week gives you some happiness
or pleasure there's a India match every
week or something right so let people
enjoy it obviously it should not be the
the one thing that your whole life
revolves around. But yes, you can have
multiple interests and and and passions.
So I I don't see anything wrong with
that. I am sure what you're trying to
say is that we should not be obsessed
with this and I completely agree with
you on that matter.
Anurag
Anurag says it's interesting to see why
China is quiet given the US's actions gi
given them a lot of precedence for them
to act regarding the Taiwan situation.
See the Chinese
their strength is econ is their economy
and their manufacturing and industrial
uh sector and obviously whatever has
whatever underlies that but military
power they are no match for the US even
in their own backyard and they simply
can't afford a military confrontation
with the US or even Japan or South
Korea.
That's why now they have realized that
this United States regime is totally
different from all other regimes and the
US is now
determined to completely transform the
world order and China has no answer to
that. That's why they're so quiet
says can you explain why F-35s imply
India is a vasal. If you see I have been
saying for for several years several
years people have been laughing at me
right I've been saying for several years
and people have been making fun of me
including very eminent people I have
been saying for several years that the
F-35
has back doors and kill switches.
I've been saying for several years that
if you purchase a F-35,
then every time you want to fly it, you
have to essentially acquire from the US
permission. It's like getting an OTP on
your phone. Without the OTP, you can't
do the thing. That sort of thing.
So to get the OTP, you have to first
send the entire flight plan to the US.
They will go through the fight flight
plan and if they agree with it, they
will give the OTP. But if you deviate
from the flight plan, your aircraft
won't allow you to use the weapons or
whatever. That is the system with the
F-35. And I have been saying that for
years and people have been making fun of
me. And now recently, who was the the
prime minister of Denmark or some
country acknowledged that that if you
own F35s, they're not you don't really
own them. So if you buy F-35s, it's like
paying tribute
to the country, to the to the United
States, to the overlord. Each F-35 must
be at least $110 million. So that's how
much money you pay to acquire something
you don't even own. Only a slave does
that. Only a vasal does that. So that's
the deal.
Okay. HC says, "What are the credible
escalation risks for GCC?"
Escalation risks for the GCC. credible
escalation risks.
Um, look, the GCC countries, they don't
really have to worry about too much
escalation. Iran will definitely target
the US installations on those countries,
US military bases, US personnel who may
be living in hotels or whatever. Beyond
that, I don't see Iran taking too much
action against the GCC countries. If
Iran is on the verge of going down, then
they could target all the oil refineries
and installations in the GCC countries.
Why not? They'll do that. As far as
civilians are concerned, Iran won't most
likely target civilians, but they will
definitely target refineries. Um they'll
target oil wells, all that they will
target if they are on the verge of going
down.
Beyond that, I don't see too much risks
for the GCC. the Iranians will target
military infrastructure, American
military infrastructure or GCC
infrastructure that the Americans are
using. Beyond that, I don't see too
much.
Godliness says, why is China so quiet?
It's abnormal because China is scared
and there's nothing China can do to
change the situation
and it's humiliating.
China is losing face. That's why they're
very quiet, very abnormal, very
unnatural. Chinese are very loud and
aggressive. What happened now? Where
have they gone? You see
Galler says Modi chose not otherwise
that this character for half a quip
officially defended our right to
tame PK knowing fully knowing the latter
being a pet of its enemy. Tame Pakistan
my PM would have followed a dharma just
as he is doing now in for Indians. India
for Indians have no combs.
Let me try and understand what you're
saying. Modi chose not otherwise
had this character for half a quip
officially defended our right to tame
Pakistan
fully knowing the Pakistan to be a pet
of its enemy US my prime minister would
have followed his dharma just as he's
doing now
India for Indians have no coms
okay I'm not entirely sure what you're
saying but all right thank you for Hey
for your views sir thank you
open to unlearn says pharma industry
benefits financially when the people are
unwell so how can you so how can you can
we expect this industry to be fair no we
can't we can't
that's why I say that in a civilized
nation
the government should tax the citizens
but if you are taxing your citizens you
have you should provide free healthare
and free education of the highest
quality. Take the taxes, take the money
from the citizens, but provide free
education and free healthare. Don't
allow education and healthare to become
businesses.
If you commercialize education and you
commercialize healthcare, it will
victimize the the citizens.
It will exploit the citizens.
Okay? So in a civilized nation,
healthcare and education should be free,
must be free as it used to be in ancient
India.
Gur TV says if Iran, the primary threat
in the Middle East for Arabs is
neutralized and sorted, then what
justification would remain for the US to
maintain its military presence in and
bases in the region? I'm sure they'll
find some. That's a great question.
So look, if Iran is neutralized and
sorted, will the Americans move out? No,
no, no, no, no. Remember NATO,
remember the cold war, 20th century?
And then what happened? USSR broke up.
So did the Americans disband NATO? No,
no, no, no, no. They expanded NATO
further and further and further further
east until the Ukraine war was in
inevitable.
So if Iran is let's say hypothetically
neutralized and sorted, what will the
Americans do? Will they maintain their
military presence? Will they dismantle
it? I expected them to expand it and
find some pretext for expanding it.
Great question sir. Really now? Really
now? Miss Patel says Kovi Shield Serum
Institute was funded by Gates 2. Okay. I
am not aware of that but okay I'll not
be surprised if that is the case.
Okay. Okay.
Um, next question. Arismantic says
requesting a fair update. What would
Iran do if India was facing the
situation instead? Iran would not let us
fully connect with Afghanistan critical
rail line not cooperation with Russia
and India for north south corridor.
So let's say India is facing the
situation that Iran is facing right now
that um
the the two major powerful nations are
attacking us.
Okay.
Iran would not let us fully connect with
Afghanistan.
Iran is not in the way between India and
Afghanistan. If you look at the map,
it's Pakistan that's between India and
Afghanistan.
Iran has nothing to do with India and
We are not able to build a critical
train line, rail line or whatever
between India Afghanistan because
Pakistan occupied Kashmir is in the way
right
that's our territory and if we had that
we would have direct access to
Afghanistan and there's nothing Iran can
do to stop us
but considering the situation
hypothetical scenario in which India is
being attacked by two major countries
more powerful than India what would Iran
Iran
would stay out of it.
Iran would stay out of it. Iran would
either remain neutral
or it may possibly bow down to those
countries and take their side for
national interest, for self-interests.
That's what Iran would do. That's a
logical
um thing to do. So that's that's what I
think Iran would do in that in that
situation.
Anup says, "Sir, you are different. You
are different. Be different. Love you
loads."
Thank you so much. Thank you. I know I'm
different and it's okay to be different.
It's okay. So, thank you so much.
Godliness says, "It's been 79 years from
47, but still our lifestyle, living
standards, eating habits, and civic
sense remain disgustful.
We can't blame everything on invaders.
uh once I moved out I don't like here
anymore. If you move out of India
and you experience the standards of
let's say first world countries
you won't like being in India anymore.
You may definitely still have an
attachment to India. You'll try and
visit as as soon as as frequently as is
as is possible because you've got family
here and got some kind of attachment to
the land. But you will not be able to
tolerate the the standards that you have
in India. Yeah. So you can't blame that
on the invaders. You can't blame that on
the invaders.
I think it's high time we we stop
blaming the invaders and Gandhi and
Nehu.
I think it's high time we stop doing
that.
Right. Prrenit Kumar says is Hindu
theocracy India's future to unite
Hindus?
Um I can't say
to unite Hindus well every single day we
have fewer and fewer Hindus in India I
don't know I don't know I can't say
where is manticor says to be honest on a
geopolitical level India standing would
go down a notch for now but Sukoy 57
purchase would enrage the US especially
if we upgrade it um I would say if we
even if we don't upgrade the soy 57 if
we purchase it that would be sufficient
to enrage the US Yeah.
So right now India's standing has gone
down more than a notch
after India has taken the side of Israel
in the US and not stood with Iran.
Even if we had not stood with Iran but
stayed neutral,
it would not not be the exact same
effect. So yes, India's geopolitical
standing
is definitely has gone down a couple of
notches right now. Suka 57 purchase
could kind of perhaps bring it up
slightly.
So yeah. Yeah.
Smith Zeri says, "Is a naval war
is a naval war being fought between the
US and Iran?" Not right now. Not quite.
Right now it's an aerial war mostly
that's being fought. Not yet a naval
war.
Godliness says India will buy $500
billion worth of goods from the US in
the coming years. I hope the US will not
be asking to buy their th AAD or F35s
out of the money. Or they will insist.
They will try their best to make us buy
everything and become completely
dependent on them. They will try their
best to arm twist India on becoming
completely
100% dependent on them. So let's see.
Let's see. I hope we don't buy those
things.
Kish S says Krish
says thanks for your work. Love from
California. Thank you so much sir. Thank
you so much. Sunny California. Love it.
Beautiful climate, beautiful weather,
beautiful everything. Thank you so much.
Putin says, "Daran Kandelwal is Russia
paper tiger? Russia without without
nukes is messed up?"
Well, it's not exactly a paper tiger,
but without nukes, it's um it stands no
chance.
Yeah. without the nukes, without the
5,000 plus nuclear warheads it has, uh,
Russia is in deep deep trouble if it
doesn't have that. So that that's the
one thing that makes Russia powerful,
those nukes.
Knowledge seeker says, will Pakistan
break? If yes, when? Well, as long as
Pakistan has American support, Pakistan
won't break.
When will it lose American support? Not
anytime soon.
So Pakistan
just to reiterate is an artificial
temporary nation. It will break and
disintegrate but that day is not soon
really. Now Miss Patel says why doesn't
the US send missionaries to the to the
Gulf vas because that is a red line.
That's a red line the Gulf nations will
never allow anyone to cross. They will
rather give up their life than to have
Christian missionaries in their lands.
And for the US, the Gulf vasals have a
lot of utility in a variety of ways and
they don't want to offend them. Get them
to do the work for them. Right? So
that's why the US doesn't do it.
As Montor says, missed several sessions
was free only today. Thank you for your
contribution. The enemy wins if we let
despair win. We must wrestle with it,
not ignore it. This is our burden and
karma. Well, thank you very much, sir.
I'm glad you're here today. Uh, and
thank you very much once again for your
very kind words, and I completely agree
with you. We must not let despair win.
Don't ignore it. Wrestle with it. Fight
it. Bear the burden and eventually we
prevail. Thank you, sir. I agree.
Bumendra Up says, "Why? What do we work
towards to change the country as it is
right now?" Because whenever people try
to bring a major change, it is met with
friction. How can we change this?
We can change this by by each of us
individually
trying to
raise our standards, be excellent and
contribute in any meaningful way to the
country. Let me give you an example.
Let's say I know that you let's say
you're not in politics. You can't do
anything to change the system. You can't
do anything to change the policies. You
can't do anything to change the
bureaucracy and so on and so forth.
You're just an individual. But how about
you become
in 10 years a multi-millionaire
then you will have the means to make
some changes in the country
in some way. Maybe at the in the private
sector or whatever you'll be able to
bring you know highquality people
together and build something construct
something. My point is each of us
individually can contribute in a small
way but if 1.4 four billion people do
that it's going to be a massive change
for India that's what we do so all of us
that's what we need to do contribute in
our own own small way in some shape or
form or the other
and you do that by raising your
standards
and and you do that by succeeding
individually whatever personal selfish
dreams and goals you have work on those
and succeed
that brings more positivity more success
throughout the country. That's what you
do.
Knowledge seeker says, "Will Israel and
India strike Pakistan? If yes, but then
when?" No, not going to happen. Nope.
Arismantic says, "I meant to transport
corridor from Afghanistan to Chabahar."
From Afghanistan to Chabahar. Okay. The
north south corridor was not supported
by Iran completely. Iran was too prickly
about us finishing it. Well, Iran has we
have high issues with with Iran, right?
A transport corridor from Afghanistan to
Chabahar. If India is in that situation,
Iran will not give us that. Even if if
it was there, it would no longer be
operational. The INSTC, right,
international north south transport
corridor was not supported by Iran
completely. Iran was too prickly about
us finishing it. Yeah. Yeah. The
Iranians have been obsidant about many
things. One very small thing we once uh
requested Iran for was for Iran to to
give us some chittas. See the Asian
chitha is extinct in India because the
British massacred it. They genocided it.
Our our cheetah but some cheetahs, a
small population of chithas still exists
in Iran which is the same species as our
cat as our cheetah. So we had requested
Iran in the 20th century. Please send us
some cheetah so that we can reintroduce
the animal in our in our land. They
refused. They refused. They refused
refused. They refused for decades and
finally we got chithas from Namibia.
So the Iranians have had these
tendencies for whatever reason. I don't
know why but whatever. Shas says curious
to why Iran attacked UK and French air
base. France France air base.
most likely because those air bases are
being used for military operations
against them. That's the only reason I
can think of.
Nagarjun says Russia Ukan war has been
going on for more than a year. No, it's
been going on for close to 4 years now.
Yeah, it's been more than four years
now. February 22, now we are in March
26. 4 years. It's been going on for more
than four years. Do you think with this
do you think this war now will end in
one or two months time or it would be
going on for years? I think Iran has the
firepower but no clear goal for now.
Okay, about the Ukraine war, I don't see
it ending in the next one or two months.
I hope I'm wrong. I hope it ends next
week, but I think it's hard for me to
see that happening in the next couple of
months. I hope I'm wrong. That's a It's
been a disastrous war. Terrible for the
civilians and I hope it ends at the
earliest, but I think it's kind of
unlikely it'll happen. It will end very
soon. One or two months. I hope I'm
wrong. Yeah, Daran Kandelwala has become
a new member. Thank you very much, sir.
Welcome to the channel's membership. I
really appreciate it. Thank you.
All right, that brings me to the end of
today's live stream. Thank you.
Um,
okay, let's take this question. Sir is
getting emotional toward the war. It's
okay to take a backseat. They've blown
the hell out of Russia. It's only
practice.
Okay.
What are you talking about? What?
All right. All right people. Let's let's
end this live stream now over here. Uh
thank you so much for the questions.
Thank you for everything. Uh when should
I do the next live stream? Maybe day
after tomorrow. Maybe day after
tomorrow. Let's see. Uh there's going to
be a lot happening
in this war unfortunately. So let's do a
live stream most likely day after
tomorrow. And I'm sure there'll be a lot
more to discuss at the time. Until then,
thank you very much everybody. Take
care. Keep asking questions. Keep
raising your standards. Keep learning.
And I will see you in the next one very
soon. Until then, take care. Bye-bye.
Good night. Good day.